If you don't get in the game of home
如果你
ownership and you rent in your 20s and
在20多岁租房，30
you rent in your 30s, you're going to
多岁又租房，却不买房，那么到了
turn around in your 40s and having not
40多岁，你就会发现自己没有
built any net worth. And in fact,
任何净资产积累。 事实上，
homeowners in America are worth 40 times
美国房主的资产是
more than renters. And I'm talking about
租房者的 40 倍。 我指的是
ordinary Americans.
普通的美国民众。
&gt;&gt; But that doesn't mean that buying a home
但这并不意味着买房
made them rich, right?
就让他们发财了，对吧？
&gt;&gt; It actually does. And I'm going to go
确实如此。 我将会经历这一切
through that.
。
&gt;&gt; But am I not better off renting and
难道我租房住，把
[music] investing in the stock market? I
钱投资到股市不是更好吗？ 我
want to bust this myth because I have
想打破这个迷思，因为我
spent the last 33 years of my life
过去 33 年的人生都在
helping millions of people with ordinary
帮助数百万收入普通的人
incomes become financially free, [music]
实现财务自由，
including nine years as a financial
其中包括
adviser at Morgan Stanley and I got to
在摩根士丹利担任财务顾问的九年，我亲眼
see firsthand how everyone who came into
目睹了每一个走进
my office with an ordinary income built
我办公室的普通收入者是如何积累
wealth. And there's a formula to getting
财富的。
rich, but there's also a system to how
致富是有方法的，但让
you put your financial life on autopilot
你在不到 10 分钟内实现财务生活自动化的方法也同样存在
in less than 10 minutes. And it doesn't
。 而且它不需要
require discipline, budget, and you
自律，不需要预算，你
don't have to make a lot of money to get
也不需要赚很多钱才能
started. But unless your financial plan
开始。 但除非你的财务计划
is automatic, it will fail. But more
是自动化的，否则它将会失败。 但更
importantly, I believe the next 10 years
重要的是，我相信未来十年
will be the greatest opportunity to
将是
build wealth in our lifetime. And yet, 7
我们一生中积累财富的最佳时机。 然而，
out of 10 people right now are living
现在十个人中有七个人都是月光族
paycheck to paycheck. More than 50% of
。 超过50%的
Americans don't have savings. And most
美国人没有存款。 而且大多数
people don't know where their money
人不知道自己的钱都花到哪里去了
goes. And in fact, when we ask people,
。 事实上，当我们问人们，需
how much money would it take to totally
要多少钱才能彻底
change your life? They say $10,000. Now,
改变你的生活时？ 他们说是1万美元。 那么，
how much money do you need to spend a
你一天需要花多少钱才能
day to blow $10,000 a year? $27.40
一年花掉 1 万美元？ 每天 27.40 美元
a day. If you invested that a day for 40
。 如果你每天投资这笔钱，持续 40
years, you'd have over $4,424,000.
年，你将拥有超过 442.4 万美元。
That would be life-changing.
那将改变人生。
&gt;&gt; But just before we get into all of the
但在我们深入探讨所有
specifics and the strategies, do you
细节和策略之前，您
have any specific advice to people that
对目前正为债务问题苦苦挣扎的人们有什么具体的建议吗
are currently struggled with debt?
？
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. There's a very simple
绝对地。 摆脱债务有一个非常简单的
formula to getting out of debt called
办法，那就是领取
dole. I'd tell you to
救济金。 我本来想告诉你
&gt;&gt; listen, my my team gave me a script that
听我说，我的团队给了我一份稿子让
they asked me to read, but I'm just
我读，但我还是想尽可能用最
going to ask you um in the nicest way I
友好的方式问你
possibly can. Thank you. Thank you first
。 谢谢。 首先非常感谢您
and foremost for choosing to subscribe
选择订阅
to this channel. It is um it's been one
本频道。 嗯，这绝对是
of the most incredible crazy years of my
我人生中最不可思议、最疯狂的一年之一
life. I never could have imagined. I had
。 我做梦都想不到。 我
so many dreams in my life, but this was
一生中做过很多梦想，但这绝对
not one of them. And the very fact that
不在其中。
these conversations have resonated with
这些对话能引起
you and you've given me so much feedback
你的共鸣，你给了我这么多反馈，这一点
is something I will always be
我将永远心存
appreciative of. And I almost carry away
感激。 我几乎背负着
a sort of burden of uh responsibility to
一种偿还你的责任感
pay you back. And the favor I would like
。 今天我想
to ask from you today is to subscribe to
请您帮个忙，
the channel if you um would be so
如果您
obliged. It's completely free to do
愿意的话，请订阅我的频道。 这样做完全免费
that. roughly about 47% of you that
。 经常收听本频道的听众中，约有 47%
currently don't subscribe to this
目前没有订阅本
channel. So, if you're one of those
频道。 所以，如果你也是这样的
people, please come and join us. Hit the
人，请加入我们吧。 点击
subscribe button. It's the single free
订阅按钮。 这是
thing you can do to make this channel
你能做的唯一一件免费的事情，却能让这个频道变得
better. And every subscriber sort of
更好。 每一位订阅者都相当于
pays into this show and allows us to do
为这个节目付费，让我们能够做得
things bigger and better and to push
更大更好，并不断鞭策
ourselves even more. And I will not let
自己。
you down if you hit the subscribe
如果你点击订阅按钮，我绝不会让你失望
button. I promise you. And if I do,
。 我向你保证。 如果我真的这么做了，
please do unsubscribe, but I promise I
请取消订阅，但我保证我
won't. Thank you. [music]
不会。 谢谢。  [音乐]
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; David, what has your mission been for
大卫，过去三十年来你的使命是什么
the last three decades?
？
&gt;&gt; I have spent the last 30 years of my
我过去 30 年的
life helping ordinary people, people
人生都在帮助普通人、
with ordinary incomes become financially
普通收入的人实现财务
free. And the last 20 years I've spent
自由。 过去20年，我一直致力于
helping people become automatic
帮助人们成为
millionaires. So, I love to teach anyone
百万富翁。 所以，我乐于教
at any income level, minimum wage,
任何收入水平的人，包括最低工资、
living paycheck to paycheck. You might
月光族等等。 你可能
be in debt. You might be struggling.
负债累累。 你可能遇到了困难。
I've taught millions of people how they
我已经教会了数百万人如何
can improve their life financially.
改善他们的财务状况。
That's what I've been dedicated to. And
这就是我一直致力于的事情。
I spent 33 years total in the financial
我在金融服务行业一共工作了33年
service industry.
。
&gt;&gt; And is this conversation just for people
这场对话只针对
that are in their 20s or is it
20多岁的人，还是
applicable to everybody at every age?
适用于所有年龄段的人？
&gt;&gt; It's applicable to everybody at every
这适用于各个年龄段的每个人，
age because whatever your age is, it you
因为无论你多大年纪，你
know, look, Stephen, so many people are
知道，斯蒂芬，
living paycheck to paycheck right now in
现在
this country. What's happening right now
这个国家有太多人都是月光族。 现在的情况
is that seven out of 10 people are being
是，十个人中有七个人在
left behind financially. Seven out of 10
经济上被落下。
people right now are living paycheck to
现在十个人中有七个是月光族
paycheck. When you go into looking at
。 如今，当你审视
finances in America today, half of
美国的财务状况时，你会发现，有一半的
Americans can't get their hands on
美国人拿不出
$1,000 in case emergency purposes. And
1000美元以备不时之需。
my biggest fear, why I updated this book
我最大的担忧，也是我更新这本书
and why I decided to come back out one
并决定
more time and do another financial
再次发起金融
literacy campaign is I'm afraid people
知识普及活动的原因，是害怕人们
are being left behind. I think with AI
会被落下。 我认为，随着人工智能的发展
right now, the next 10 years is going to
，未来十年将是
wealth in our lifetime.
我们一生中积累财富的最佳时机。
That's the good news. The bad news is a
这是个好消息。 坏消息是
lot of people being left behind. My goal
很多人被落下了。 我
today, next hour is very simple. I want
今天，也就是接下来一个小时的目标非常简单。 我想
to give you the system on how to become
向你传授一套方法，让你
an automatic millionaire at any age
无论年龄
level, at any income level. But what I'm
大小、收入水平如何，都能成为自动百万富翁。 但我
going to teach you is how to put your
要教你的是如何用不到 10 分钟的时间让你的
financial life on autopilot in less than
财务生活实现自动化
10 minutes. Because when your financial
。 因为当你的财务
life is automatic, your habits work
生活自动化时，你的习惯也会
automatically. And an automatic
自动养成。 自动化的
financial life doesn't require
财务生活不需要
discipline, doesn't require a budget,
自律，不需要预算，
and you don't have to make a lot of
而且你也不需要赚很多
money to get started.
钱才能开始。
&gt;&gt; Why should people be taking advice from
人们为什么要就此事听取
you on this subject matter? What's what
你的建议？
have you done in those 33 years?
这33年里你都做了些什么？
&gt;&gt; I've been doing this my entire life.
我这辈子都在做这件事。
Right? So, if you go all the way back, I
正确的？ 所以，如果追溯到很久以前，我
started investing at the age of seven.
从七岁就开始投资了。   事情的起因
And how that happened is I had a
是我有一位
grandmother, amazing grandmother. Her
很棒的祖母。 她的
name was Grandma Rose. At 30, she made a
名字叫罗斯奶奶。  30岁那年，她做出了一个
decision that changed the whole destiny
改变我们整个家庭命运的决定
of our family. And the decision she made
。 她做出的决定
was she want to be poor anymore. And at
是，她不想再过贫穷的生活了。
30, on a very cold day on her birthday,
30岁那年，在她生日那天，天气非常寒冷，
she turned to my grandfather and she
她转向我的祖父
said, "We don't have any money. We're
说：“我们没钱了。我们只能勉强维持
living paycheck to paycheck and I don't
生计，我不想在
want to retire here. I want to go to
这里退休。我想去
California. I want to be where it's
加州。我想去
warm." And my grandfather said, "Well,
温暖的地方。” 我祖父说：“那
what do you want to do about it?" and
你想怎么做呢？”
she's like, "We need to change what
她说道：“我们需要改变
we're doing or nothing will change." And
我们正在做的事情，否则一切都不会改变。”
so my grandmother started saving 50
于是，我奶奶开始
cents a week out of her paycheck. So 50
每周从工资里存下 50 美分。 所以
cents each because they were like middle
每人 50 美分，因为他们就像
class people, right? Didn't have a
中产阶级一样，对吧？ 没有接受过
college education. My grandfather worked
大学教育。 我祖父
in a plant. My grandmother worked in
在工厂工作。 我祖母在
retail. But she started saving small
零售业工作。 但她开始存下一些
amounts of money. And over her lifetime,
小钱。 在她的一生中，
she became an investor. And she became a
她成为了一名投资者。 她白手起家，成为了
self-made millionaire. My first book,
百万富翁。 我的第一本书，
which you have sitting over here, was a
就是你现在看到的这本，书名
book called Smart Women Finish Rich. It
叫《聪明女人致富之道》。 那
was the lessons that my grandmother
是我祖母
taught me. So, at seven, my grandmother
教给我的道理。 所以，在我七岁那年，奶奶
took me to McDonald's and she taught me
带我去麦当劳，她教了我
a lesson that would change my life. She
一个改变我一生的道理。 她
said, "David, you're sitting here eating
说：“大卫，你坐在这里吃
McDonald's and cheeseburgers and your
麦当劳、芝士汉堡、
French fries and your milkshake." She
薯条和奶昔。” 她
said, "I'm going to teach you today how
说：“今天我要教你如何
to be rich for real. You like to play
真正致富。你喜欢玩
Monopoly. Here's my lesson today." She
大富翁游戏。这就是我今天的课程。” 她
said, "There's three types of people.
说：“人分三种。
those like you who are here eating right
像你们现在正在这里吃饭的
now, you're what's called a consumer.
，你们被称为消费者。
She said the people over there who have
那边那些一直在
been working, they're called employees
工作的人，他们被称为员工，他们拿着
and they've been working for minimum
最低
wage and that's a very hard way to live.
工资，生活非常艰难。他们当时
85 cents an hour. And she said the third
每小时只挣85美分。第三种
type of person is the person who owns
人是
this place. They're called an investor.
这家店的老板，他们被称为投资者。她
And she said, "Today, I'm going to teach
说：‘今天，我要教
you how to buy stock in McDonald's so
你们如何购买麦当劳的股票，这样
that when you come to McDonald's, you'll
你们每次来麦当劳，就能从
make money from everybody who's here.
在场的每一个人身上赚钱。’”   “
When your friends come to McDonald's,
当你的朋友来麦当劳，
you'll make money from them, and you'll
你就能从他们身上赚钱，你就能
be an owner of McDonald's." And she took
成为麦当劳的股东。”她带
me down to a brokerage firm, helped me
我去了一家证券公司，帮我
buy my first share of stock at
买了我的第一股
McDonald's.
麦当劳股票。
That moment changed my life because what
那一刻改变了我的人生，因为
she made me realize is like everything
她让我意识到，就像
that we do, I'm seven years old.
我们做的每一件事一样——我当时才七岁——
everything that we do, there's an
我们做的每一件事都蕴含着
opportunity to be an investor and own
成为投资者并拥有
that. So like at nine years old, I'm at
它的机会。所以，九岁的时候，我在
Disney. I'm like, "Hey, Mickey Mouse,
迪士尼乐园里，问：“嘿，米老鼠，
are you public?" So I was like not a
你是上市公司吗？”从某种意义上说，我跟
normal kid in that way because I started
一般的孩子不太一样，因为我
investing at a young age.
很小就开始投资了。
But then I made a lot of mistakes. Then
但后来我犯了很多错误。然后
I went to college. Then I got myself in
我上了大学。然后我欠了
credit card debt. Then I believed all
信用卡债。然后我信了
the myths that young people often
年轻人常
believe. I believed I couldn't really
信的那些谬论。我以为只有
invest a lot until I made a lot of
赚了很多
money. So, in my early 20s, I was making
钱才能真正进行大规模投资。所以，在我二十出头的时候，我虽然
money but spending everything. So, I was
赚了钱，但却把钱都花光了。就这样，我
went from making nothing to making
从一无所有到年收入
$50,000 a year and I'm still broke. I'm
五万美元。 一年过去了，我还是没钱。我
like, well, it's not enough money. So, I
心想，这钱根本不够用。于是，我
went to $75,000 a year, still broke,
把年收入提高到7.5万美元，还是没钱，
spending more. Then I got to $100,000 a
花钱更多了。后来，我的年收入达到了10万美元
year in income. Lot of money, right? In
。很多钱，对吧？我才
my 20s. Oh my god, I'm rich. No, I was
二十几岁。天哪，我发财了。不，那时候我的支出
still spending more than I was making at
仍然大于收入
that point. I was a financial adviser
。我是一名财务顾问，这
&gt;&gt; that was my job. I was working at Morgan
就是我的工作。我在摩根
Stanley helping people plan for
士丹利工作，帮助人们规划
retirement teaching retirement seminars
退休，举办退休讲座。
and I met this ordinary couple that came
我遇到了一对普通的夫妇，
into my office at the age of 52, Jim and
吉姆和苏·麦金泰尔，他们52岁，来我的办公室咨询
Sue McIntyre. They had an ordinary job.
。他们有一份普通的工作。
That year they had made a little over
那一年，他们的收入略高于
$53,000.
5.3万美元。
Their average income over their lifetime
他们一生的平均收入
was $40,000.
是4万美元。52岁那年
And at 52, Jim put out all the
，吉姆把所有的
statements on a table in front of me. I
财务报表都摆在我面前的桌子上。我
sat there and added them up and they had
坐在那里，把它们加起来，发现他们的
a net worth of $1.8 million.
净资产是180万美元。
And I sat back at a table just like this
然后，我靠在一张桌子旁，就像这样…… 他们
and said, "How did you do this?"
问：“你是怎么做到的？”当时
And they had just been in my class for
他们才上了我的课
four weeks. They're like, "David, we did
四个星期。他们说：“大卫，我们做了
a lot of what you talked about, but we
很多你讲的内容，但我们
didn't have a budget because budgets
没有预算，因为预算根本
don't work." and they talked about why
行不通。”然后他们解释了为什么
budgeting didn't work for them. They
预算对他们不起作用。他们
said, "We put everything on autopilot.
说：“我们把一切都交给了自动驾驶系统。”   “
We saved money automatically for
我们所有开销都自动存钱
everything."
。”
And that was the moment that changed my
那一刻改变了我的
life. I [snorts] realized that day as
人生。那天我（嗤笑）意识到，作为一个
paycheck with a high income. These
收入很高却仍然月光族的人，这些
people had half the income that I did
人收入只有我的一半，却能在
and they were able to retire at 52. I
52岁退休。我当时才
was in my mid20s and I realized that if
二十五六岁，我意识到，如果
I didn't start saving and investing, if
我不开始储蓄和投资，如果
I didn't change, nothing was going to
我不做出改变，一切都不会
change and I would never have the
改变，我永远也无法拥有
financial freedom that they had. And so
他们那样的财务自由。所以
I went home that day and I changed
那天回家后，我彻底改变了
everything in my life. Now I had a lot
自己的人生。我有很多
of bad habits. So I had a lot of things
坏习惯，有很多事情
that needed to be changed. You were the
需要改变。您
senior vice president at Morgan Stanley
在摩根士丹利担任高级副总裁
when you stepped down and you soon after
时离职，之后不久就
wrote this book called Smart Women
写了一本书，名为《聪明女人
Finish Rich. It begs the question, what
致富》。这不禁让人思考，在您的
your process of financial education that
理财教育过程中，您观察到
women face versus men?
女性和男性在理财方面面临哪些差异？
&gt;&gt; I started I was in business with my
我最初和我
father and we had a lot of older clients
父亲一起做生意，我们有很多老年客户，
and I would sit in on meetings one after
我经常参加她们与
another with widows. So in the first
寡妇的会议。所以在
month of my career, I sat in three
我职业生涯的第一个月，我就参加了三场这样的会议。 我当时要见
meetings with three widows where the
三位
husband had dropped dead suddenly. And
丈夫突然去世的寡妇。
my dad at the time was teaching these
我爸当时正在教
women how to read their brokerage
她们如何看证券账户
statements, how to write checks, and how
报表、如何写支票，以及如何
to know if they would have enough money.
判断自己的钱够不够用。
And I thought, "This is crazy." And I
我当时就想，“这太疯狂了。”
said to my dad for the third
第三次见面时，我问我爸，
appointment, "Dad, what do you what
“爸，你觉得这是怎么回事
what's going on here?" And he's like,
？”他问，
"Well, what do you mean?" I go, "Well,
“什么意思？”我说，“
you're teaching these women when their
你竟然在教这些
husband has just died how to handle
丈夫刚去世的女人如何
their finances." And he said, "David,
理财。”他说，“大卫，
not all women are like your grandmother.
不是所有女人都像你奶奶那样。”   “
Your grandmother was a rarity." And I
你奶奶是个特例。”我
said, "Dad, that's crazy. I'm going to
说：“爸爸，这太不可思议了。”  “我要
go out and teach a class for women and
出去开个女性
money." And when I started teaching the
理财课。”当我开始教
class for women money, here's what I
女性理财课时，我
learned. Here are the things that make
学到了以下几点。以下是
women different than men when it comes
女性在金钱方面与男性不同的几个方面
to money. Women, first of all, live
。首先，女性
longer than men, which [clears throat]
比男性寿命更长，这
means they need more money than men do.
意味着她们比男性需要更多的钱。
57, Stephen. Now it's 59.
斯蒂芬，我最初写那本书的时候，美国女性的平均丧偶年龄是57岁。现在是59岁。
Okay. You do all these shows on
好的。你做了很多关于
longevity. It seems like everybody's
长寿的节目。好像每个人都
living forever. They're not. Okay. The
长生不老似的。其实不是。好的。
average age of widowhood in America is
美国女性的平均丧偶年龄是
59 years old.
59岁。
&gt;&gt; When you say widowhood, you mean the age
你说的丧偶是指
in which a woman becomes a widow.
女性成为寡妇的年龄。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. They're married and they lose
没错。她们结婚后失去了
their husband.
丈夫。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, so women are often wiped out
好的。所以，女性在经济上往往会因此遭受重创
when that happens financially. Second
。第二
thing is that women are hurt more than
点是，女性在离婚时比男性受到的伤害更大
men when it comes to divorce.
。
The third thing that affects women is
第三点是，女性的
that they work fewer years. I'm like,
工作年限较短。我想，
these are just the the the the
这些只是……
statistical realities. Women work fewer
统计数据表明，女性的工作
years than men because they have
年限比男性短，因为她们要
children. So that's an average of
生育子女。平均而言，女性的工作年限比男性
somewhere between 7 to 11 years less.
少7到11年。
And that's less money going into social
这意味着她们缴纳的
security, retirement accounts, and it
社保和退休金更少，这会
affects their earnings and often they
影响她们的收入，而且她们的
earn less. So what I have taught for
收入往往更低。因此，我
third nearly 30 years now is as a woman,
近30年来一直强调的是，作为一名女性，无论
I don't care what your situation is. I
你的处境如何，
don't care if you're an entrepreneur. I
无论你是企业家、
don't care if you're a stay-at-home
全职
mother. I don't care if you're married
妈妈，还是
to local bank president. I don't care if
银行总裁，无论你是
you're married, singled, widowed,
已婚、单身、丧偶还是离异，
divorced. As a woman, you have to be in
作为一名女性，你必须
charge of your finances. Period. Drop
掌控自己的财务。就这么简单。无需
End of discussion. You can't delegate
多言。你不能把
your financial well-being to anyone
自己的财务健康委托给任何人
else. You have to be in charge. Now, I
。你必须自己掌控。此外，
will also tell you, Stephen, that women
斯蒂芬，我还要告诉你，女性
make better investors than men. They
比男性更擅长投资。她们之所以
they make better investors than men
比男性更擅长投资，是
because often women don't trade like men
因为女性的交易方式通常与男性不同，
do and they are they do more research
她们在投资前会做更多的研究。
before they invest and their performance
投资，而且他们的表现
is better. They're way better long-term
更好。他们在长期
investing than men are.
投资方面比男性强得多。
&gt;&gt; I heard some [clears throat] stats once
我曾经听过一些统计数据，
upon a time that men are
说男性是
the majority of the gambling addicts.
赌徒中的大多数。
&gt;&gt; Well, I'm sure they're the majority of
嗯，我确信他们是
the gambling addicts. And also when you
赌徒中的大多数。还有
look at trading because trading's become
交易，因为交易现在
a very big thing, but trading's always
非常流行，但交易一直
been a thing.
存在。
&gt;&gt; Trading meaning
交易指的是
&gt;&gt; trading like trading stocks, buying and
像股票交易那样
selling stocks. Now it's buying and
买卖股票。现在还包括
selling cryptocurrency, buying and doing
买卖加密货币、买卖
selling options. All these things are
期权。所有这些
primarily men doing it and they don't
主要都是男性在做，但他们
make money because the bulk of people
赚不到钱，因为绝大多数
who trade lose money day in day out in
交易者日复一日、年复一年地赔钱
year out. I teach a philosophy which is
。我教授的理念是
this. Your money and your investments
这样的：你的金钱和投资
should be boring. Your life should be
应该枯燥乏味。你的生活应该
interesting. Your investments should be
精彩纷呈。你的投资应该
boring. If someone's coming to a
枯燥乏味。如果有人在
cocktail party talking about their
鸡尾酒会上谈论他们的
investments and it's exciting,
投资，而且听起来很激动人心，那肯定有
something's wrong with it.
问题。
&gt;&gt; Why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; Because sexy is how you go broke when it
因为在金钱方面，性感会让你破产
comes to money. Boring is beautiful when
。当谈到财富时，枯燥乏味才是美
it becomes when it's about your wealth.
。
So, [snorts] even driving over here, my
所以，（嗤之以鼻）甚至开车 我
son was just like, "Dad, why aren't you
儿子当时就问我：“爸爸，你为什么不
trading Tesla stock?" I'm like, "You
交易特斯拉股票？” 我说：“你
know why I'm not trading Tesla stock?
知道我为什么不交易特斯拉股票吗？”
Because you can't make money trading.
因为交易赚不到钱。
You got to figure out when to buy, when
你得弄清楚什么时候买，什么时候
to sell. I want my kids investing in
卖。 我希望我的孩子投资
index funds. I have my clients investing
指数基金。 我的客户投资的是
in index funds. Boring is beautiful when
指数基金。 在金钱方面，平庸反而是一种美
it comes to money.
。
&gt;&gt; Before we get into the real specifics
在我们深入探讨具体细节
and the tactical strategies and um we
和战术策略之前，我们先来
think about a bunch of the sort of
思考一下
things you said about debt and credit
你刚才提到的关于债务、
cards and saving and getting out of debt
信用卡、储蓄、摆脱债务
and how to become wealthy and an
以及如何致富和成为
automatic millionaire. Is there anything
百万富翁的一系列问题。 从世界大局的角度来看，我们有什么
we should discuss as it relates to the
需要讨论的吗
the world? Whether it's wealth
？ 无论是财富
inequality, whether it's the amount of
不平等，还是靠
people that are living paycheck to
工资度日的人数
paycheck, what I'm trying to get a
，我都想了解
Western world.
西方世界的金融财富状况。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, so let's talk, you know,
。 好，那我们就来聊聊，你知道，
when people talk about economies. Here's
人们谈论经济的时候。 在
here's the economy that matters in my
我看来，这才是真正重要的经济因素
opinion. Your economy, meaning the
。 你的经济，也就是
that you're in control of is yours.
你掌控的经济，就是你的经济。
You're not in control over what's going
你无法控制
to happen with interest rates, what's
利率的走向、地缘
going to happen with geopolitical
政治的走向以及
things, what's going to happen with AI.
人工智能的发展。
The only economy that you can control is
你唯一能掌控的经济体系就是
yours. Now, here's the question.
你自己的经济体系。 现在，问题来了。
Are you working?
你在工作吗？
Most cases, the answer is yes. The
大多数情况下，答案是肯定的。
average person will work 90,000 hours
普通人一生平均工作9万小时
over their lifetime. So, if you are a
。 所以，如果你是
dual income household, you're going to
双职工家庭，那么
hours, the two of you, over your
你们两个人
lifetime. You're going to actually make
一生中将要工作 9 万到 20 万个小时。 你这
millions of dollars over your lifetime.
辈子真的会赚到数百万美元。
The question is with your own economy,
问题是，就你自己的经济状况而言，
are you going to keep any of the money?
你打算留下多少钱？
[snorts] And the sad thing for many
[嗤之以鼻] 可悲的是，对很多
people is that they're not. I I say most
人来说，事实并非如此。 我认为大多数
people have what I call a no plan. Money
人都没有计划。 资金
comes in, money goes out. And they say,
流入，资金流出。 他们说：
"Well, I don't know where the money all
“我不知道钱都到哪
went." And I go, "That's called a no
里去了。” 我说道：“那叫做没有
plan." A person who's an automatic
计划。” 一个天生的
millionaire, the moment money comes in,
百万富翁，一旦有了钱，
they have a plan for exactly where it's
就会立刻计划好钱要怎么花
going to go. And it starts with paying
。 而这一切都始于他们先给自己发工资
themselves first.
。
automatically.
自动地。
&gt;&gt; A lot of people listen to this and if I
很多人都在听这个，如果
go back if I go back just over 10 years
我回到十多年前
in my life, I would have been sat
，我就会坐在那里
listening to this conversation in £7,000
听着这段对话，同时背负着 7000 英镑
of debt. And I would have thought, God,
的债务。 我当时想，天哪，
like I'm becoming a millionaire, that's
我怎么可能成为百万富翁呢？那还远着呢
a that's a million miles away, no pun
，我可不是在开玩笑
intended. I to become a millionaire, I'm
。 要想成为百万富翁，我
going to have to earn so much more
必须赚更多的
money. And at the time, I was working in
钱。 当时，我在
call centers. It it would have just felt
呼叫中心工作。 感觉那里离自己
so far away. And I say, you know, people
很遥远。 我说，你知道，人们连
are struggling to feed their children,
养活孩子都困难，更
let alone become a millionaire.
别说成为百万富翁了。
Is it far away for the average person?
对普通人来说，那里很远吗？
&gt;&gt; It's far away if you don't know the
如果你不了解
strategy. There's a strategy to getting
策略，那目标就遥不可及。
out of debt. There's a strategy to
摆脱债务是有策略的。
building wealth. There's a system.
积累财富是有策略的。 这里有个系统。   其中
&gt;&gt; How much of it is just earning more
有多少仅仅是赚了更多的
money? Because when I have these
钱？ 因为当我在
conversations on my show, I think the
我的节目中进行这些对话时，我认为
surprisingly untouched territory is we
令人惊讶的未被触及的领域是，我们
don't teach people how to become more
没有教人们如何变得更
valuable so that they can earn more
有价值，从而让他们赚更多的
money. A lot of it's about like index
钱。 很多内容都跟指数
funds or savings, whatever. But how much
基金或储蓄之类的有关。 但其中有多少只是
of it is just like I need to get higher
因为我需要获得
valued skills in the market?
市场上更有价值的技能呢？
&gt;&gt; We know for a fact that making more
我们确切地知道，赚更多的
money doesn't make you rich. So, so
钱并不会让你变得富有。 所以，就像
people can go, as I told you earlier,
我之前跟你说的那样，人们可以从
like from $100,000. They can go from
10 万美元起步。 他们的收入可能从
50,000 to 100,000 and still be broke.
5 万涨到 10 万，但仍然会破产。
They can go from a h 100,000 to 200,000
他们的年收入可能从 10 万增加到 20 万，
a year and still be broke. They can go
但仍然会破产。 他们的收入可能
from 200,000 to 300,000 and still be
从 20 万涨到 30 万，但仍然会
broke. In the US, when you take
破产。 在美国，
households that make $150,000 a year,
年收入 15 万美元的家庭中，有
one out of three of them are still
三分之一仍然
broke. When you peel back the curtain
破产。 当你揭开帷幕，
and you ask why is that? Well, we know
问为什么会这样？ 我们知道
things cost more, but we also know
物价上涨了，但我们也知道
there's massive lifestyle creep, right?
生活方式正在发生巨大的变化，对吧？
you get you get around other people who
你接触到的都是
are making more money and then you spend
收入更高的人，然后你就会花
more money. And the reality is these
更多的钱。 而现实情况是，这些
phones are designed to get you to spend
手机的设计目的就是让你把钱都花光
everything, right? Today with the
，对吧？ 如今，借助
algorithms, there's better technology
算法，我们拥有比以往任何时候都更先进的技术来
today than there's ever been to get you
让你
to spend more money. And nobody wants
花更多的钱。 没有人希望
you to spend money once. They want you
你只花一次钱。 他们想让你
to spend money for a lifetime, right?
一辈子都花钱，对吧？
It's a lifetime value of a customer. So
这是客户的终身价值。 所以，
there's a battle for our income. And
一场争夺收入的战争正在上演。
everyone wants a piece of it. It starts
每个人都想分一杯羹。 这一切要从
with the government. like you go to work
政府说起。 就像你上班，早上
and you go to work at 9ine and you
9 点上班，然后
actually work from nine o'clock to 12
从 9 点工作到 12 点处理
for taxes. Now, this is an important
税务事宜一样。 这其实是一个很重要的
lesson actually. The government doesn't
教训。 政府不会
ask you to budget to pay taxes. They
要求你为缴税做预算。 他们会
take your taxes from you automatically.
自动从你的账户中扣除税款。
They take social security from you
他们会自动从你的账户中扣除社保金
automatically. They're they take the
。 他们会
money from you automatically because
自动从你那里拿走钱，因为
they know you won't have anything to
他们知道
give if they don't take it from you.
如果不拿走，你就没钱给别人。
Then people work from 12 to about 3:00
然后人们从中午 12 点工作到下午 3 点左右，
for housing and food and then from 3:00
为了住房和食物，然后从下午 3 点
to 5:00 for all the rest all the rest of
到 5 点工作，为了其他所有的
things.
事情。
The people who build wealth in America
在美国乃至全世界，那些积累财富的人，
and really all over the world, they do
他们做的
something different. They keep the first
事情都与众不同。 他们保留
hour a day of their income.
每天收入的第一个小时。
&gt;&gt; What do you mean by that? So what that
你这话是什么意思？ 所以这
means is whatever you earn, you could be
意味着，无论你挣多少钱，你可能
making minimum wage, you could be making
只挣最低工资，也可能每小时挣
$20 an hour, $30 an hour, $40 an hour.
20 美元、30 美元或 40 美元。
Whatever you earn, the first hour day of
无论你挣多少钱，
your income has to go to you. You're the
你当天收入的第一小时都必须归你所有。 你是
first person who gets paid.
第一个拿到报酬的人。
&gt;&gt; And you mean you have to save it, invest
你的意思是说，你要把它存起来，投资
it.
出去。
&gt;&gt; You have to invest it. So how do you
你必须投资。 那么，如何才能在
without paying taxes? The answer is you
不缴税的情况下投资一天中的第一个小时呢？ 答案是：
pay yourself first using a 401k plan.
先通过 401k 计划给自己发工资。
So, if you have a job with a retirement
所以，如果你有一份工作，并且有退休
account, 401k plan, you sign up and you
账户或 401k 计划，你就注册并
use that plan. Now, I can't just stop
使用该计划。 现在，我不能就此止步
right there, right? Because because it
，对吧？ 因为
sounds so simple, like, okay, I'll use
听起来很简单，所以，好吧，我就按
my plan. No, you have to know the
我的计划来吧。 不，你必须知道如何
formula to using your plan to be rich.
运用你的计划才能致富。
We know after 40 years now exactly what
经过40年的发展，我们现在确切地知道，
you need to do if you want to be a
如果你想成为百万富翁，你需要做什么
millionaire. I can tell you how to
。 我可以告诉你如何从
20s so that you're done by the time
20多岁开始成为百万富翁，并
you're in your mid-50s. You save a
在50多岁时实现这个目标。 你节省的
little one hour of your income is 12 and
一小时收入是
a.5% of your gross revenue. I went on
你的毛收入的 12.5%。
online today to look at what's the
今天我上网查看了有关
latest statistics with 401k
401k百万富翁的最新统计数据
millionaires. The new stats that just
。 富达刚刚发布的新统计数据
came out from Fidelity. There are
。
people in Fidelity 401k plans that are
富达401k计划中有654,000人
now millionaires.
现在都是百万富翁。[嗤笑]
&gt;&gt; What is a 401k?
什么是401k？
&gt;&gt; Okay,
好的，
&gt;&gt; because you know we've got a lot of
因为你知道我们有很多
global listeners. There's different
全球听众。
types of 401k in every country. So in
每个国家的401k计划类型都不一样。 所以在
the US, a 401k plan is a retirement
美国，401k 计划是一种退休
account. It is a retirement account that
账户。 这是
the company has set up, right? And it
公司设立的退休账户，对吗？ 而且它还
allows you to put money away tax
能让你存下可以抵税的钱
deductible. They call it pre-tax. In
。 他们称之为税前。
most countries, you have a deductible
大多数国家都有可抵税的
retirement account, but it depends on
退休账户，但这也要看具体
the country, too, right? Like in Canada,
国家，对吧？ 就像在加拿大，
it's a different type of plan than it is
它的计划类型与
in Australia, than it is in Italy, than
澳大利亚、意大利和
it is here in the UK. Almost every
英国的都不同。 几乎每个
country though has some form of
国家都有某种形式的
retirement account and has the ability
退休账户，并且可以
to put money away automatically. Here's
自动存钱。
the problem, and I'll use the US
问题是这样的，我特意以美国为例，
specifically because it's where I do
因为我的
most of my work in the US. Those who
大部分工作都是在美国完成的。 那些
have a 401k plan,
拥有 401k 计划的人，
the ones that are millionaires, what
那些百万富翁，
they did, here's the formula, the exact
他们是如何做到的，以下是公式，确切的
formula. They saved 14% of their gross
公式。 他们储蓄了总收入的 14%，
income and their employer had a small
他们的雇主还额外提供了一小部分
match on top of that. And then how they
匹配资金。 然后，他们如何
invested the money is key because it's
投资这些资金才是关键，因为
not enough to just put money in these
仅仅把钱存入这些
401k plans. You have to be invested for
401k 计划是不够的。 要想获得成长，就必须进行投资
growth. And growth means stocks, right?
。 增长就意味着股票，对吧？
So you'd have to have and and the actual
所以你必须拥有……而我刚才提到的
specific allocation in these 401k
这些401k百万富翁的实际具体资产配置比例
about 70% stock and 30% bonds.
约为70%股票和30%债券。
Okay. Now, what are people doing that
好的。 那么，那些未能实现这一目标的人都在做什么呢
aren't achieving this? Well, the average
？ 嗯，
American saving maybe 3 or 4%. Maybe 5%
美国人平均储蓄率可能在 3% 到 4% 之间。
if they have a 401k plan. People who
如果他们有401k计划，那可能占5%。
don't have 401k plans in many cases
很多情况下，没有 401k 计划的人
aren't even doing this. They can they
甚至都不会这样做。 他们
can open up an IRA account, but in most
可以开设个人退休账户（IRA），但在大多数
cases, they're not doing that. So, the
情况下，他们并没有这样做。 所以，
whole secret is
秘诀就在于
not budgeting, not using discipline,
不做预算，不运用自律，
having the money move right from your
让钱直接从你的
paycheck. paycheck gets deposited
工资里扣除。 工资会自动存入
it hits your bank account automatically
您的银行账户，然后会在工资自动到账的当天优先用于
first for retirement. Then later we'll
退休储蓄。 之后我们会
talk about building a security account,
讨论如何建立一个安全账户，如何
building a dream account. The key is
建立一个梦想账户。 关键在于
that the money moves automatically.
资金自动流动。   顺便
the way 24 million millionaires now. So
一提，现在美国有2400万百万富翁。 因此，
in the US in just 20 years.
短短 20 年间，美国的百万富翁人数就从 800 万增加到了 2400 万。
How did they do that? There's two
他们是怎么做到的？
primary escalators to wealth. That is
通往财富的途径主要有两条。 那就是
stocks and real estate. And if you're
股票和房地产。 如果你
not in stocks and you're not in real
不投资股票，也不投资
estate, you are being left behind.
房地产，你就落后了。
&gt;&gt; When you say real estate, does that mean
你说的房地产，是指
having a mortgage and owning a h home?
拥有抵押贷款和一套房子吗？
&gt;&gt; It's owning a home or owning REITs?
是选择拥有房产还是拥有房地产投资信托基金（REITs）？   房地产投资
&gt;&gt; REITs.
信托基金（REITs）。   房地产投资
&gt;&gt; REITs. Real estate equity investment
信托基金（REITs）。 房地产权益投资
trusts. So, that's another way to buy
信托基金。 所以，这是另一种
real estate without actually having to
无需实际
own the home, but you don't get the same
拥有房屋即可购买房地产的方式，但你无法获得同样的
level of returns.
收益。
&gt;&gt; I mean, this is um this is one of the
我的意思是，嗯，这是
hot topics of conversation we've had on
我们节目中多次讨论过的热门话题之一，
this show several times is many of my
我的很多
guests that are sort of financial
嘉宾，也就是财务
advisers say that owning a home is a bad
顾问，都说拥有房产是一项糟糕的
investment. I think from what I
投资。 根据我的
understood from the research and from
研究和
reading your books that you feel
阅读您的著作后我的理解，我认为您
differently about that.
对此有不同的看法。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I mean I I couldn't feel more
。 我的意思是，
differently when we look at where is
当我们审视
wealth created in the United States and
美国和国外财富的创造地点时，我的感受截然不同
also abroad. It's in two places. It's in
。 它出现在两个地方。 它投资于
home equity and it's in the stock
房屋净值，也投资于股票市场
market. So when you look at housing and
。 所以，当我们审视住房问题时，以
you take someone who owns a home and
拥有住房的人为例，
we'll talk about I know it's hard to buy
我们来谈谈，我知道
homes right now but when you look at
现在买房很难，但当我们比较
people who own a home versus people who
拥有住房的人和
rent homeowners in America follow this
租房的人时，请美国房主们注意这
for one second. Homeowners in America
一点。 在美国，房主的资产
are worth 40 times more than renters. So
是租房者的40倍。 所以，
the average homeowner in America today
如今美国普通房主的
is worth over $400,000.
净资产超过40万美元。
&gt;&gt; But this doesn't establish causation.
但这并不代表存在因果关系。
I.e. that doesn't mean that buying a
IE。 但这并不意味着
home make made them rich, right?
买房就让他们发财了，对吧？
&gt;&gt; It actually does. And I'm going to go
确实如此。 接下来我将详细讲解一下
through that here. So the average renter
。 所以，平均每个租房者的
is worth $10,000,
身价是 1 万美元，
right? So why why does buying a home
对吗？ 那么，为什么买房能
build wealth? and how much wealth in the
积累财富呢？
United States is now in home equity.
美国目前有多少财富是以房屋净值的形式存在的？   《
Wall Street Journal just ran an article
华尔街日报》两天前刚刚刊登了一篇
on this came out two days ago. There's
关于此事的文章。
$34 trillion now in home equity in
目前美国房屋净值总额达34万亿美元
America. This number has gone up 90%
。 这个数字比之前增长了 90%，
the other money is in retirement
其余的钱都在退休
accounts which is 60 70% in stocks.
账户里，其中 60% 到 70% 是股票。
There's $45 trillion now in retirement
目前退休账户总额高达45万亿美元
accounts. So those two things alone
。 所以光这两项就
equal $80 trillion dollar, right? Like
价值 80 万亿美元，对吧？ 就像
when you want to go like where are the
你想找
breadcrumbs? Where is wealth being
面包屑的时候一样？ 财富在哪里
created? It's right in front of us. Now
创造？ 它就在我们眼前。 现在
the problem that we have in the United
我们在美国面临的问题是
States, but also look, we're here in
，但你看，我们
London right now. Problem we have in so
现在身处伦敦。
many cities is that real estate keeps
很多城市面临的问题是，房地产价格不断
going higher and higher and higher and
上涨，而
people's incomes are not keeping pace
人们的收入却跟不上
with the cost of buying a home. So, when
购房成本的上涨。 所以，当
someone comes on a show like this and
有人上这样的节目
says, "Look, you don't have to buy a
说：“听着，你没必要
home. It's cost more to have a house
买房。买房
than rent. You, you know, I I watched
比租房贵。你知道，我看过
one of the shows. I won't say who it
一个节目，我就不说是谁
was. It doesn't matter. They all say the
了，反正都
same thing. Don't buy a house. You'll be
一样。别买房，你会被
trapped. You'll have to pay you'll have
困住的。你得
to pay real estate taxes and you'll have
交房产税，还得
to pay insurance and things break." They
交保险，而且东西还会坏。” 他们
go through all these expenses
列举了所有这些费用，听起来好像是：
and it it makes it sound like, "Oh,
“哦，
yeah. If I rent it'll be cheaper." No.
是的，如果我租房会更便宜。” 不。
Who who do you think pays these expenses
你觉得租房的时候谁来支付这些费用
when you rent?
？
You do. The landlord passes the cost of
你做。 房东最终会将
these expenses on to the renter
这些费用转嫁给租客
ultimately. Why do they do this? Because
。 他们为什么要这样做？ 因为
people who buy real estate buy it for an
购买房地产的人是为了
investment. They buy it for an
投资。 他们购买它是为了
investment. They're not they're not
投资。 他们并没有
subsidizing these costs. So, it's a hard
补贴这些费用。 所以，
thing to hear and especially when you're
听到这种话很难受，尤其是对
young. Like I have a a son who's 22.
年轻人来说。 我有个儿子，今年22岁，
He's in Chicago. He's going to move to
他在芝加哥。 他要搬去
New York City. It'll be extremely hard
纽约市。 他马上开始工作
for him to buy a place in New York when
后，想在纽约买房会非常困难
he starts working right away. Just will
。
be probably won't for two or three
可能两三
years. A lot of young people when they
年内都不会。 很多年轻人
move to a major city, they can't afford
搬到大城市后，都
to buy right away. When I came out of
买不起房。 我大学毕业时
college, like you, I was in credit card
，和你一样，也背负着信用卡
debt. I had $12,000 in credit card debt.
债务。 我当时欠了12000美元的信用卡债。
I remember opening up my bills and
我记得当时打开账单，
having the room spin and thinking, I'm
感觉天旋地转，心想我永远也
never get out of credit card debt. how
摆脱不了信用卡债务。
am I going to buy a house? But I did.
我该如何买房？ 但我确实这么做了。
And in fact, I didn't buy a home when I
事实上，我年轻的时候并没有独自买房
was young by myself. I bought a home
。 我和我最好的朋友一起买了一套房子
with a best friend. So, how did I get my
。 那么，我的
first house? First house we bought was a
第一套房子是怎么来的呢？ 我们买的第一套房子价值
quarter of a million dollars. We put 10%
二十五万美元。 我们付了10%的
down and my best friend and I, Andrew,
首付，我和我的好朋友安德鲁
we split that down payment. So, we each
平分了这笔首付。 所以，我们每人
put $12,500 down. This is how we scraped
首付了 12500 美元。 我们就是这样凑齐了所有东西
it together. The house was a complete
。 那房子需要彻底
fixer upper and we didn't have enough
翻修，我们没有足够的
money to make the mortgage payments. So,
钱支付抵押贷款。 所以，
we rented out bedrooms and we had
我们出租了卧室，也让
friends rent bedrooms and that helped us
朋友们租我们的卧室，这有助于我们
cover our mortgage. We scraped it
支付房贷。 我们凑齐了所有东西，
together and that's what a lot of people
很多年轻人都是这么做的
do when you're young. But if you don't
。 但是，如果你不
get in the game of home ownership and
参与购房置业，
you rent in your 20s and you rent in
20多岁租房，
your 30s, you're going to turn around in
30多岁也租房，那么到了
your 40s and having not been built any
40多岁，你就会发现自己没有任何
net worth. When I wrote the automatic
净资产积累。  20年前我写了《自动
millionaire 20 years ago, two things
百万富翁》这本书，从那以后发生了两件事
have happened since then.
。
The stock market has gone up in 20 years
股市在20年内上涨了
600%.
600%。
&gt;&gt; Okay? So, if you had a $100,000, just
好的？ 所以，如果你原本有 10 万美元，现在就变成了
that is gone to $600,000.
60 万美元。
If you bought a house, the house has
如果你买了一套房子，那么这套房子的价格已经
gone up 400%.
上涨了 400%。
So, when you read this book with all
所以，当你阅读这本书时
these, there's a a whole chapter of
，你会发现其中有一整章都是
updated success stories. There are a lot
最新的成功案例。 很多
of ordinary people that started saving
普通人
5, 10, 15, $20 a day, bought a starter
每天存下 5 美元、10 美元、15 美元、20 美元，买了一套入门级
house, and today they're millionaires.
住房，如今他们都成了百万富翁。
&gt;&gt; So, am I not better off renting
所以，我租房
[clears throat] and investing in the
（清嗓子）投资
stock market
股市是不是
versus buying a house? Because obviously
比买房更划算？ 很显然，
when I when I when I buy a house, I'm
当我买房时，我需要
paying a premium on the house so that I
支付一定的溢价才能
can get a mortgage. I want to bust this
获得抵押贷款。 我想打破这个
myth because what happens is people come
迷思，因为人们会说，
on they go the stock look I can tell you
股票市场……我可以告诉你，
right now the stock market over the last
过去
20 years has averaged over 10% annually
20年股市的年均收益率超过10%，
people go the returns are better in the
人们会说
stock market than the real estate yeah
股市的回报比房地产好，没错，
but that's not applesto apple comparison
但这并不是公平的比较。
why
为什么
you buy a piece of real estate when you
你买的是房地产？买房的时候，
buy a home people don't typically pay
人们通常不会用
cash for their first house they put down
现金买第一套房，他们会付
20% and they borrow the other 80%. So
20%的首付，剩下的80%是贷款。 举
you take like an example of a take a
个例子，假设你买了一套价值
$200,000 home. $200,000 home you put 40
20 万美元的房子。 一套价值 20 万美元的房子，你投入 4 万美元
grand in. Home goes from $200,000 to
。10 年后，房子的价值从 20 万美元涨到
400,000 in 10 years. This has happened
40 万美元。 自新冠疫情爆发以来的
to so many people in the last five years
五年里，这种情况发生在了很多人身上
since COVID. There are markets all over
。
the US where housing prices have gone up
美国各地都有房价上涨
100 to 200%. So a person buys a $200,000
100% 到 200% 的市场。 假设一个人购买了一套价值 20 万美元的
home, they borrowed 80%. It's doubled.
房子，他贷款了 80%。 翻了一倍。
So they've made 200,000 in profit. They
所以他们赚了20万。 他们
didn't put in 200,000, they put in 40.
没有投入20万，而是投入了4万。
So, they got a five times return on
因此，他们的首付获得了五倍的回报
their down payment. They go to sell
。 他们去卖房子
their house.
。
They don't pay taxes on the gain because
他们无需为收益缴税，因为
when you own a home, at least in the
在
United States, you own a home for over
美国，拥有房产的时间必须超过
two years. If you're single, you get
两年。 如果你是单身，你可以获得
$250,000 in taxfree gains. If you're
25 万美元的免税收益。 如果你
married, you get over half a million
已婚，你将获得超过五十万
dollars in taxree gains. You get tax
美元的免税收益。 房贷可以享受税收
deductions on the mortgages. So, what
减免。 所以，
happens is people come here and they go,
人们会来这里，然后说：
"You know what? You shouldn't be you
“你知道吗？你
shouldn't be tied down. You need to be
不应该被束缚。
flexible when you're young. You don't
年轻的时候要灵活。你不想
want to have the responsibility
承担责任，
and you should take the extra money and
你应该把多余的钱
you should put it in a mutual fund. And
投到共同基金里。”
you know what happens in the real world,
你知道现实世界是怎么回事吗，
Stephen? People don't do that. They rent
斯蒂芬？人们根本不会这么做。他们租
an apartment that's nicer than what they
一套超出自己经济能力范围的公寓，把
money and then they turn around in their
钱都花光，到了
mid30s and they have no equity because
30多岁，发现自己一无所有，因为
they haven't bought anything and they
他们既没买房也
also haven't saved money.
没存钱。把本来
could have used to buy a house and
可以用来买房的钱
they're going to put it in the stock
投到
market. They don't do that. And that's
股市，这完全是无稽之谈。他们根本不会这么做。顺便说一句，这也是
why also, by the way, corporate America
为什么美国企业
got into the game of buying up real
开始在
estate all over America, houses, and
全美各地收购房地产，包括房屋和
building apartments to rent to an entire
公寓，然后出租给整整
generation, hoping these people never
一代人，希望这些人永远不会
buy
买房的原因
this. Like 10 days ago, Trump came out
。就在10天前，特朗普
and basically said he wants the
公开表示，他希望
institutions out of buying up all the
机构投资者退出房地产市场。
homes in America. Why does he want to do
他想让全美国的房子都买下来。他为什么要
that? because he because he recognizes
这么做？因为他意识到，
how serious of a problem it is to have a
让一代又一代的美国人租房居住是一个多么严重的问题
generation of Americans who are renters.
。
I'm telling you, when you look at
我告诉你，当你看看
average Americans, average, I'm talking
普通美国人，我说的是
about ordinary Americans. When you look
普通的美国人。当你
at where their wealth is, it's in home
看看他们的财富在哪里，你会发现它们都集中在房屋
equity and it's in the stock market. And
净值和股市里。
this is the last thing I'll say,
最后一点，
better or worse through home equity. So
无论好坏，代际财富都是通过房屋净值积累起来的。所以，
when you look at why you know you asked
当你探究原因时，你就会明白，
if a family doesn't buy a home the
如果一个家庭不买房，
likelihood the next generation can buy a
下一代买房的可能性
home is very low because it's this when
就非常低，因为当
someone dies
有人去世时，
the money that is in the house that home
房子里的钱，也就是房屋
equity is often what transfer transfers
净值，通常会转移
to the next generation helps the next
给下一代，帮助
generation buy a house. I was looking at
下一代买房。我在
some stats here because I want to what I
这里查阅了一些统计数据，因为我想……
want I wish I could sit
我希望我能坐下来，和
&gt;&gt; sit down all of the guests that have
所有上过
been on my show that have had a
我节目、持有
difference of opinion and have said that
不同意见、认为
buying a house is a bad
买房不好的嘉宾
&gt;&gt; it could [clears throat] be a really
好好聊聊，他们可能会……（清嗓子）
interesting conversation. Right.
有趣的对话。没错。
&gt;&gt; It would be a really interesting
这会是一场非常有趣的
conversation. What I've done as an
对话。我采取的
alternative to that approach is I've
另一种方法是，我把
pulled up what they've said
他们说过的话整理出来，
&gt;&gt; and I'm going to give you some of the
然后把其中一些
things they've said just so so you can
内容分享给你，这样你就可以
rebuttle them um and have your say on
反驳他们，并发表你的看法
them. One of the things that they often
。他们经常
say is that long-term real
说的一点是，美国长期实际
inflationadjusted home price
房价（经通胀调整后）每年
appreciation in the US is about 1%
大约上涨1%，
annually and one of my guests cited
我的一位嘉宾引用了
Robert Schiller as the evidence of that.
罗伯特·席勒的言论作为证据。扣除
After maintenance um which usually
维护费用（通常
equals 1 to 2% um property taxes which
相当于1%到2%）、房产税（
equals about 1% insurance and
约占1%）、保险和
transaction costs the net real returns
交易成本后，实际净收益平均
approach roughly zero on average. So
接近于零。所以，
when you say housing is a great
当你说住房是一项很好的
investment, are you referencing the
投资时，你指的是
gross appreciation which is the the the
总增值，也就是
total appreciation or the net returns
总增值，还是扣除
after taxes, maintenance, insurance, and
税收、维护、保险和
selling costs?
销售成本后的净收益？
&gt;&gt; So when you dig into these kind of
当你深入研究这类
numbers like this,
数字时，你会发现
what they are is they're numbers, but
它们只是数字，但
they're not real world, right? And so
它们并不代表现实世界，对吧？所以，当
like when you when you talk to someone
你和
who owns a home today and they've owned
现在的房主交谈时，他们会告诉你…… 拥有
it for 20 years and you ask them how
房产20年，你问他们
much of your net worth is now in the
现在净资产中有多少是房产
equity in your house
净值，
over 50% of their net worth is in their
超过50%的人净资产都花在了
house. You will see people on your
房子上。你会看到
YouTube channel that literally if you
YouTube频道上有人说这不属实，如果你仔细
read the comments and I'm sure you do. I
阅读评论的话——我相信你肯定会读的。我也会读。
was I read a comment yesterday on your
昨天我在你的YouTube页面上看到一条评论
YouTube page. All I know is I bought a
。我只知道我买了一套
house and it's gone up in value three
房子，它的价值已经翻了
and a half times and the rent when I
三倍半。我买房时的租金
bought the house was $1,200 and the rent
是1200美元，而
today to buy that if I had that house if
现在如果我租这套房子，租金
I was renting it would be $4,000.
就要4000美元了。
So the thing is you have to understand
所以你必须明白，
is that rents always go up, Stephen.
租金总是在上涨，斯蒂芬。
Like I lived in New York City for 18
比如，我在纽约住了18
years.
年。
When I moved to New York City in 2001,
2001年我搬到纽约的时候，
a really nice apartment, a nice
一套很不错的公寓，一套很不错的
apartment was like $6,000 a month. When
公寓，月租大概6000美元。当
I left New York, that same apartment was
我离开纽约的时候，同样的公寓
$25,000 a month. Follow the follow the
月租已经涨到了25000美元。想想这其中的
insanity of that math. Now, that
疯狂吧。 那套
apartment went from being $2 million
公寓从价值200万美元的
apartment to a $5 million apartment. So,
公寓涨到了500万美元的公寓。所以，
I could have been renting it, but in my
我本来可以租的，但
case, I owned it and it went up in value
我买下了它，它的价值也上涨了
$3 million.
300万美元。
So, I have friends who have been renting
我有些朋友
in New York for 20 years. They have
在纽约租房住了20年，却
built no net worth. I have no vest
一无所获。我跟你们的
interest in this conversation. Meaning,
谈话没有任何利益关系。我的意思是，
I don't sell real estate. I'm not a real
我不卖房，我不是
estate agent. I'm not selling real
房地产经纪人，我也不卖房
estate. I've just seen in the real world
。我只是亲眼目睹了
how people have built wealth. the the
人们是如何积累财富的。比如
the McIntyres in this book, the
这本书《
automatic millionaire, when they came
自动百万富翁》里的麦金泰尔夫妇，他们
into my office and they were worth $1.8
来我办公室的时候，身价180
million and he was 52 and able to retire
万美元，当时52岁的他已经可以退休了，
having earned an average of $40,000 a
年均收入4万美元
year.
。
All their money wasn't in the stock
他们的钱并没有全部投入
market. They had bought a home in San
股市。他们在加州圣莱安德罗买了一套房子
Leandro, California, what he what they
，那里是他们
called a middleclass neighborhood. Their
所谓的“中产阶级社区”。当时他们的
home at the time was worth about
房子价值大约
$300,000.
30万美元。
They had paid their mortgage off and
他们还清了房贷，之后又
they had bought one more house on their
买了一套房子。
street. They rented the first house.
他们住在一条街上。他们先租了第一套房子。后来又
They bought a second house on their
在这条街上买了第二套房子
street. They paid that mortgage off. And
。他们还清了房贷。
so they owned two homes free and clear.
这样，他们就拥有了两套房子，而且产权清晰。一套房子可以出租，
One house they got income from. One
另一套房子可以自住，
house they lived in with no debt. And
没有债务。
then they had saved money in their 401k
此外，他们还在401k退休计划中存了钱
plan. So, if I was a young person or not
。所以，如果我是一个年轻人，或者
even a young person, a middle-aged and
甚至不是年轻人，一个中年人或
older person who took my down payment
老年人，我把原本打算用来
that I was going to pay into the house,
买房的
if let's say it was say my down payment
首付（比如说
was $20,000 and I put that into the S&amp;P
2万美元）投入到标普
500 instead over the long run, won't
500指数基金中，从长远来看，
that grow larger than the total home
这笔投资的增长难道不会超过房屋
equity potentially?
净值吗？
&gt;&gt; Here's why the index fund theory doesn't
这就是指数基金理论行不通的原因
work.
。
You can't live inside an index fund.
你不可能住在指数基金里。
You can't live inside a mutual fund. You
你也不可能住在共同基金里。
have to live somewhere as long as you're
只要你活着，你就得住在某个地方
alive. Here's what people should do.
。人们应该这样做：
Take a look at what you're paying in
看看你每月支付的
rent.
房租是多少。
Now, ask yourself a question. If I'm
现在，问问自己一个问题。如果我
paying 5,000 a month in rent, which lots
每月支付5000美元的房租，很多
of people are, right? Do you know people
人…… 没错吧？你认识
paying 5,000 a month in rent?
每月房租5000美元的人吗？
&gt;&gt; Yes.
认识。好的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, they're paying 60,000 a year.
那他们一年就付6万美元。
Let's take that number.
我们就按这个数字算。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; So, over 10 years, they're going to
那么，10年下来，他们
spend $600,000 in rent.
要花60万美元的房租。
Yeah.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; If the rent doesn't go up,
如果房租不涨，
&gt;&gt; in 20 years, they're going to spend 1.2
20年后，他们要花120
million in rent. If the rent doesn't go
万美元的房租。如果房租不
up, in 30 years, they will have spent $2
涨，30年后，他们要花200
million in rent if the rent doesn't go
万美元的房租
up. But the rent does go up. So, the
。但是房租确实会涨。所以，
question you just have to ask yourself
你只需要问问自己
is, am I going to take all this money
，我难道要把所有这些钱都花在
that I'm spending on rent and never
房租上，却
build anything?
什么都不做吗？
And if you really believe that renting
如果你真的认为租房
is better than owning, then you should
比买房好，那你
still consider the idea of buying
还是应该考虑买房而不是让
something than that somebody else rents.
别人租房。
Cuz I promise you, somebody's getting
因为我保证，总有人会
rich in the transaction. If you're the
从中获利。如果你是
renter, you're not the one who's getting
租房者，你可不是那个
rich in the transaction of renting. It
从中获利的人。
is a great short-term solution renting.
租房是一种很好的短期解决方案，但
It is not a great term long-term wealth
并非长期财富
building solution. The other thing that
积累的理想选择。
people often talk about and you you
人们经常谈到的另一点，也是您
cited earlier is the mobility that
之前提到的，是
renting gives you.
租房带来的流动性。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Your son was here a second ago. He's 16
您儿子刚才来过，他16
years old. Yeah. Soon he'll be
岁。很快他就会到了
&gt;&gt; at the age where he's got his own place
拥有自己住所的年纪，开始
and he's thinking about different career
考虑不同的职业发展
opportunities and oh my god AI is this
机会，天哪，人工智能现在可是个
big thing. So he might want to go to San
大技术。所以他可能想去
Francisco. Then he might want to go live
旧金山，也可能想去
in Florence and wherever else. if he's
佛罗伦萨或其他任何地方。如果他
bought a place, there is a interesting
买了房子，这其中既有
sort of psychological but also financial
心理因素，也有经济
component to the fact that it makes it
因素，那就是买房会让他
harder for you to move with the
更难抓住
opportunity of life. And if we are if if
人生机遇。如果我们
what people say about the future of work
对未来工作的看法
is true, that we're going to have many
是真的，我们
more careers in our lives than we did in
一生中会拥有比过去更多的职业
the past, one might assume that we're
，那么我们或许可以假设我们的
also going to be more mobile. And so, is
流动性也会更强。那么，
there an argument to say that buying a
买房
house might hurt my prof professional
是否会损害我的职业发展
opportunities, my ability to pursue
机会，影响我追求
professional opportunities? The answer
职业的能力呢？ 机会？答案
is possibly, right? But here's the thing
是有可能，对吧？但
about rent. Rent's, interestingly
说到租金，有趣的是
enough, a major obligation, right?
，租金是一项重大的负担，对吧？
Usually, when you go and you do a lease,
通常情况下，当你签订租赁合同时，
you lock yourself into a one-year lease.
你会签一年的租约。
Sometimes you lock yourself into a
有时甚至会签
two-year lease.
两年的租约。
When you buy something, and this is
当你买房时——
assuming that you have the money to buy
假设你有足够的钱买房
something, Stephen,
，斯蒂芬，赶紧
look up because you've got all the data
去查一下，因为你手头就有所有数据
at your fingertips here. Look what the
。看看在美国
average length of time it takes to sell
卖房的平均时间是多少
a home in the United States. Just just
。
Google that right now because what I
现在就去谷歌一下，因为我
will tell you is in certain markets you
要告诉你的是，在某些市场，你把
can put your home on the market and you
房子挂牌出售，
can sell it in less than 90 days. Now
不到90天就能卖掉。
some markets you can sell your home in
有些市场甚至
less than 30 days. In many cases
不到30天就能卖掉。在很多情况下，
you own something than when you rent.
拥有房产实际上比租房更灵活。
And that's if you want to sell it. It
当然，前提是你想卖房。数据
says the average time from listing to
显示，到2025年，从挂牌到成交的平均时间
sale is about 47 to 62 days from listing
约为47到62天
to closing in 2025, including 16 days on
，其中包括16天的
the market and 30 to 45 days to close.
市场停留时间和30到 45天就能完成交易。
&gt;&gt; That's called less than 2 months.
这叫不到两个月。
&gt;&gt; Even in hot markets, the process from
即使在火热的市场，从
putting a house on the market to legally
挂牌出售到合法
selling it can take 1.5 to 3 months.
成交也需要1.5到3个月。这
Meaning home equity isn't a quickly
意味着房屋净值并不是一项可以快速
accessible investment.
获得的投资。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But do you think that's pretty
是啊。但你觉得这算
quick? 90 days.
快吗？90天。
&gt;&gt; No, it is. It is quick. I mean it takes
不，确实很快。我的意思是，
takes you that amount of time to get out
解除租约也需要这么长时间
of a lease.
。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. So now so so here you've got a
没错。所以现在，你拥有一
piece of property that you can turn
处房产，可以
around and sell in less than 90 days.
在不到90天内转手卖掉。
Now this is the US. You can't do that.
这是在美国。你做不到这一点。
Like for inance I live in Italy. That
比如，我住在意大利。
could be very hard to do that in Italy.
在意大利，这可能非常困难。
But in the US you've got something
但在美国，你拥有的房产处于
that's in a good market. It's liquid.
良好的市场行情。它流动性强。
The other thing is you can rent it,
还有一点是，你可以把它出租，
right? You're you're actually not
对吧？你实际上并没有被
trapped. If if you start to build equity
困住。如果你开始积累
in your home and you pay your mortgage
房屋净值，并
down slightly, next thing you know
稍微减少一些抵押贷款，接下来
you're able to rent that property and
你就可以出租这处房产，而且
you can still move. Today, people are
你仍然可以搬家。 如今，人们把
taking their homes and they're Airbnbing
自己的房子放到Airbnb上出租
them. What I really want for people is
。我真正希望的是人们有
the chance to be financially free.
机会实现财务自由。
There's also an age at which it doesn't
而且，到了某个年纪，拥有房产就变得不再
matter if you own. You know, once you
重要了。你知道，一旦你年纪
start to get older and you've built
渐长，
financial security, you get in your 50s
经济稳定下来，到了五六
or your 60s or 70s and you just want to
十岁甚至七十岁，你只想去
travel and you don't want to own
旅行，不想拥有
anything. That's a different stage of
任何东西。那是人生的另一个阶段
life. So, the question just becomes
。所以，问题就变成了
the money that you make. I go back to
你赚多少钱。我再说回之前
the 90,000 hour comment. When you make n
提到的“9万小时定律”。当
when you work 90,000 hours over your
你一生工作9万小时，赚到
what's your plan to keep some of this
这么多钱后，你打算如何留住一部分
money?
？
You have to have a pay yourself first
你必须制定一个“先付给自己”的
plan. That has to be your number one
计划。这必须是你的首要
priority is that when you earn money,
任务：当你赚钱时，
the first person who you're going to pay
首先要支付给自己
is you. If you say, you know what, I
。如果你说：“你知道吗，我
watched Stephen and I saw David and I've
看过斯蒂芬的节目，也看过大卫的
seen a bunch of other people on his show
节目，还看过其他一些人的节目，
and I'm not going to buy a house. Okay,
但我不会买房。” 好吧，
then
那
you have to pay yourself first more. Now
你得先多给自己发点工资。过去
I go around the world for the last 30
30年里，我周游世界，
years starting with Oprah with the
从奥普拉的《
automatic millionaire. I launched this
自动百万富翁》节目开始。我
book on Oprah and I talked about you
在奥普拉节目上推出了这本书，我谈到你
have to save 1 hour a day of your income
必须每天从收入中拿出1个小时来储蓄。
and people will get on these social
人们会在社交
media boards and be like I can't save
媒体上抱怨说，我连
10% of my income.
收入的10%都存不下，
They'll I can't live off 90% of my
我不可能靠90%的
income. It's not possible. I have to
收入生活，这根本不可能，我必须把钱
spend all of it. Right? Well, then that
全花掉。对吧？那么，那些
person who's renting and not buying a
租房而不是买房的人（买房
house, which is for savings, is clearly
是为了储蓄），显然
never going to save. So, the other thing
永远也存不下钱。买房的另一个好处
about buying a house is it does require
是，它确实需要
force savings because when you use have
强制储蓄，因为当你需要
a mortgage payment, part of that
支付房贷时，其中一部分
mortgage payment is paying down your
是用来偿还
debt. And I teach you how to use a
贷款的。我会教你如何使用
bi-weekly mortgage payment plan. So, you
双周还款计划。也就是说，你
take a 30-year mortgage and you pay it
选择30年的房贷，
off five years earlier. And doing that
提前5年还清。这样做
can save you, depends on the size of the
可以帮你省钱，具体金额取决于房屋的大小
home, can save you $50 to $100,000 just
，光是这笔钱就能帮你省下5万到10万美元。
in interest payments. You talk about
利息支出。你提到要
having a savings mindset.
培养储蓄意识。
What is a savings mindset and how does
什么是储蓄意识？
one go about saving if they are one of
如果
those people that says, "Listen, I'm
有人说：“听着，我现在
barely getting by as it is, David."
勉强糊口，大卫。”那该如何存钱呢？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是啊，
&gt;&gt; How how the hell am I going to save
我现在债务越来越多，我怎么可能存钱呢
getting into more debt right now?
？
&gt;&gt; So, the first thing is you have to find
所以，首先你得弄清楚
your money, right? So, what I what I
你的钱都花到哪儿去了，对吧？
find, Steve, is when I talk to people,
史蒂夫，我发现，当我跟人们交谈时，
most people don't know where their money
大多数人不知道他们的钱都花到哪儿
goes. Literally, they don't know.
去了。真的，他们不知道。
They're like, I'm like, "How much money
他们会问，我就问，“
you spend a month?" Well, I'm not really
你一个月花多少钱？”嗯，我不太清楚。
sure. How much money you spend a year?
你一年花多少钱？
Well, I'm not really sure. You need to
嗯，我也不太清楚。你需要
be sure. So, you should be doing
弄清楚。所以，你应该想办法
something to track where your money
追踪你的钱都花到哪儿
goes. Now, you can be sophisticated. You
去了。你可以用更高级的方法。你
can use apps. It will track where your
可以用应用程序。它们可以追踪你的
money goes. You can also take out a pad
钱都花到哪儿去了。你也可以拿出
of paper and I give people a 7-day
纸笔，我给人们布置了一个为期
financial challenge for seven days. Just
七天的财务挑战。
bring a little pad of paper with you and
你只需要带上一个小纸笔，
write down every single day where your
每天把你的钱都记下来
money goes. Now, why do I want people to
。我为什么要大家这样
do that? Because most people today are
做呢？因为现在大多数人都是
spending money unconsciously. I go back
无意识地花钱。就拿
to these phones. The fact that I don't I
手机来说吧，我现在
don't even have to carry a wallet
甚至都不用带钱包了
anymore, right? It's just click click
，对吧？只要点点点，
click and pay for things. We've lost
就能付款。我们已经失去了
touch with spending money. So, when
对花钱的感知。所以，当
people start to see what they're really
人们开始意识到自己到底
spending, it's a wakeup call. The
花了多少钱时，就会幡然醒悟。
biggest thing I've been sharing lately
我最近一直在分享的重点
is what does it take to blow $10,000 a
是：如果每天要花掉1万美元，
year per day in terms of spending? How
一年下来需要多少钱？
much money do you need to spend a day to
你每天要花多少钱才能
blow $10,000? Now, show us the per here.
花掉1万美元？现在，给我们看看这个。
Now, we happen to have these are we have
我们今天正好有
pounds today, right? So, um so I I'm
磅，对吧？嗯，我
holding Stephen right now. I'm holding
现在拿着斯蒂芬。我拿着一块，也就是
what is known as a brick.
所谓的“砖头”。
So, I don't know if your staff told you
我不知道你们的工作人员有没有告诉你们
how much I'm holding here. You know how
我手里拿着多少。
much what you guess I'm holding?
你们猜猜我手里拿着多少？
&gt;&gt; It looks like maybe $5,000.
看起来大概有……  5000美元。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, this is a life-changing amount
好的。斯蒂芬，这是一笔足以改变人生的
of money, Stephen. This This is $10,000
巨款。这是10000美元
right here.
。那么，一年下来，每天要花多少钱才能
&gt;&gt; And what does it take to blow $10,000
花掉10000美元呢
in a year per day? How much money you
？你
have to spend per day to go through
每天要花多少钱才能花掉
$10,000? I'll make it easy for you. The
10000美元？我给你简单解释一下。
the answer is $27.40
答案是每天27.40美元
a day. $27.40 a day adds up equaling
。每天27.40美元，
$10,000 over the year. Now, before we go
一年下来就是10000美元。现在，在我们讨论
through where do you where do you spend
你把这
this money? How do you waste $27.40 a
笔钱花在哪里之前，在我们讨论你每天怎么浪费掉27.40美元之前
day, the question becomes, if you didn't
，问题变成了：如果你
waste $27.40 40 cents a day and you were
每天不浪费这27.40美元，并且
able to get yourself to invest $10,000 a
能够让自己每年投资10000美元
year, what could this be worth over
，那么随着时间的推移，这笔钱会值多少钱
time? And the answer is in 40 years if
？答案是，40年后，如果
this was in the S&amp;P 500 fund which you
这笔钱投资在你之前提到的标普500基金中，
quoted earlier and you earn 10% annually
并且每年获得10%的收益，
with reinvested dividends
加上股息再投资，那么……
if you invested $27.40
如果你每天投资 27.40 美元，就能增长到 440 万美元以上
a day.
。
&gt;&gt; Pass me this big brick.
把这块大砖头递给我。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
好的。
&gt;&gt; So if I save
如果我
half of this a day then in did you say
每天存下这笔钱的一半，那么，你说
40 years?
40 年？
&gt;&gt; In 40 years. So, let me give you the
40 年。那么，让我用
math on a couple different ways of doing
几种不同的方法给你算一下
this. Okay, so what would happen if you
。好的，如果你
invested roughly half of this a day? The
每天投资大约这笔钱的一半，会发生什么？
number I use is $27.40 a day. It's the
我用的数字是每天 27.40 美元。这是个
magic number. That equals $10,000 a
神奇的数字。这相当于每年 1 万美元
year. If you invested that a day for 40
。如果你每天投资 1 万美元，持续 40
years, you'd have over $4,424,000.
年，你就能拥有超过 442.4 万美元。
&gt;&gt; If I invest $27 a day, in 40 years, I'll
如果我每天投资 27 美元，40 年后，我将
have $4 million.
拥有 400 万美元。
&gt;&gt; Over $4 million. Let's go through the
超过 400 万美元。
yeah butts now because people are going
现在我们来讨论一下大家可能会疑惑的地方，因为
to hear this. Some people are going to
有些人听到这个会说：
go, "Wait, what?" And then we'll talk
“等等，什么？” 然后我们来讨论一下
about where you find $27.40 a day.
每天 27.40 美元是怎么来的。
Yeah, but $4,400,000
是的，但是……  440万美元
won't be worth a lot of money in 40
40年后不会值多少钱
years.
。
With inflation, it won't be worth that
考虑到通货膨胀，它的价值会
much. It won't have the same purchasing
更低。它的购买力会大打折扣
power. My answer would be it's worth a
。我的答案是，它的价值
whole lot more than zero. Right? If
远不止于零。对吧？如果
you're not saving any money, if you
你不存钱，如果你
can't save $27.40 40 cents a day, you
每天连27.40美元都存不下，你就
won't have $4,400,000.
不可能拥有440万美元。
Yeah, but with taxes, you know, it won't
是啊，但是你知道，加上税收，它不会
grow that much. Well, it could if it was
增长那么多。嗯，如果
in a retirement account. You wouldn't be
放在退休账户里就有可能了。你不用
paying taxes on the money. Yeah, but
为这笔钱缴税。是啊，但是
it's not possible to earn 10% on my
我的钱不可能赚到10%的收益
money. Well, the stock market for over a
。嗯，
hundred years has averaged over 10%
一百多年来，股市的平均
annually with reinvested dividends.
年收益率（包括股息再投资）一直超过10%。
Yeah, but the stock market's risky and
是啊，但是股市风险高，也很
complicated. Well, no, it's not. If you
复杂。嗯，不，并非如此。如果你
bought an index fund, it's actually not
买的是指数基金，它实际上并没有
that risky and complicated.
那么高的风险和复杂。
Yeah, but I don't know. I don't know how
是啊，但我不知道。我 不知道怎么
to get started. Well, you could start
开始？其实入门
really easily. You could open up a
很简单。你可以开一个
brokerage account. You could go to a
证券账户。你可以去嘉信
Charles Schwab, Fidelity. I mean, I'm
理财（Charles Schwab）、富达投资（Fidelity）。我的意思是，我接下来会一一介绍
literally going to go through them all.
。
Vanguard, Robin Hood, Coinbase, Acorns,
先锋集团（Vanguard）、罗宾汉（Robinhood）、Coinbase、Acorns，
and in less than 10 minutes, you could
不到十分钟，你就能
open up an account and be saving. Pick a
开户开始存钱。选个
dollar amount. $5 a day, $10 a day, $27
金额，每天存5美元、10美元、27美元
a day, and that could change your life.
，这就能改变你的人生。
Now, why is $10,000, Stephen, such an
斯蒂芬，为什么1万美元这么
important dollar amount? Here's what I
重要呢？我从事
can tell you, having done this for 30
这行30年了，我可以告诉你，
This dollar amount right here, first of
首先
all, this is
，
in a bank account right now. So, this is
现在每两个美国人中就有一个银行账户里没有1000美元。所以，1万美元是
10 times what one out of two Americans
美国人存款的10倍
have. But more importantly, $10,000.
。但更重要的是，1万美元。
When we do surveys
当我们做调查，
and we ask people, "How much money would
问人们“多少钱才能
it take to totally change your life?"
彻底改变你的人生？”时，
The answer is not a million dollars. The
答案不是一百万美元。 美元。
answer is not $100,000.
答案不是10万美元，而是
The answer is actually$10,000.
1万美元。
And the question is, why is it 10,000?
问题是，为什么是1万美元？
And the reason is is that's about what
原因在于，这大约是
the average person has in credit card
普通人信用卡
debt. And they feel like they're
债务的总额。
drowning like you talked about earlier.
就像你之前说的，他们感觉自己快要被淹没了。
and they know that that could pay off
他们知道这笔钱可以还清
their credit card debt. Or they have a
信用卡债务。或者，他们有一份
job they don't like and they if you knew
不喜欢的工作，如果他们知道，
that if they had $10,000
只要
in a savings account, they'd quit that
在储蓄账户里存上1万美元，他们就会辞职，
job and they'd be free. They'd have to
获得自由。他们可能
go find another job
不得不另找工作，
&gt;&gt; or start a business or something
或者创业，或者更糟糕的是，
they're in an abusive relationship and
他们可能身处一段虐待关系中，
they can't leave. But if they had
无法离开。但如果他们有
$10,000, they'd leave. So, you know, a
1万美元，他们就会离开。所以，你知道，
lot of people go, "David, you just make
很多人会说：“大卫，你把
this all too simple." And it's true. I
事情说得太简单了。”确实如此。我之所以这么说，是
do because when it's simple, people take
因为当事情简单易懂时，人们才会采取
action on it. So for years, I have
行动。因此，多年来，我一直在
taught this concept called the latte
教授这个叫做……的概念。 拿铁
factor. [snorts] A lot of people love me
效应。[嗤之以鼻] 很多人因此喜欢我
for it. Now I have a lot of people hate
。现在也有很多人因此讨厌
me for it. And I have taught that, you
我。我一直教导大家，
know, we waste small amounts of money on
我们会在一些小事上浪费小钱
little thing. I had your staff bring me
。我让你的员工给我拿了杯
a nice coffee. Um, when I started
好咖啡。嗯，当我开始
teaching the latte factor, I would talk
讲授“拿铁效应”的时候，我会谈到
about the idea that we waste five bucks
我们
a day on coffee. And that if you don't
每天在咖啡上浪费五美元。如果你不
believe you can start saving and
相信自己可以开始存钱和
investing,
投资，
at least save $5 a day. Make your coffee
至少每天省下五美元。自己在家做咖啡
at home. And people would say, "But I
。人们会说：“但我
don't want to give up my coffee." Okay.
不想放弃咖啡。” 好吧。
Well, then figure out another way to
那就想想别的办法
save $5 a day. This iced coffee, I don't
每天省下五美元。这杯冰咖啡，我不
know what it costs here in London. In
知道在伦敦多少钱。在
New York City, that coffee right there
纽约，这杯咖啡要
is $9.50
9.5美元，
plus a tip.
加上小费，
It's over 11 bucks. I know because I was
超过11美元。我知道，因为我
just in New York. So
刚去过纽约。所以
today we we had a bunch of props here
今天我们这里有很多道具，
and I said, "Well, let's try to show
我说：“好，我们来演示一下
like what what is $27.40." Like when I
27.4美元是什么。” 就像我
go to my hotel later when I leave here,
我离开这里后回酒店，
a cocktail is going to be 30 bucks,
一杯鸡尾酒要30美元，
right? I was just in New York City
对吧？我刚在纽约
cocktail. I had a cocktail in my hotel
喝过鸡尾酒，在酒店喝的一杯鸡尾酒要
was $31.50.
31.50美元，
Wine $50. Eating out. You go and have
葡萄酒50美元。出去吃饭，你
lunch today, it's going to be $25. And
今天去吃午饭，要25美元。
people say, 'Well, I have to eat.' And I
人们会说：“好吧，我得吃饭。”
go, I know you do, but you could also
我知道你会这么做，但你也可以自己带
brown bag your lunch. It's what my
午饭。我
grandmother did. Now, her friends teased
奶奶就是这么做的。她的朋友们都取笑
her. But my grandmother was able to
她。但我奶奶
retire to California. And her friends
退休后搬到了加州。而她的朋友们
all got stuck in Milwaukee, Wisconsin,
都困在了威斯康星州的密尔沃基，
where it was cold because they couldn't
那里很冷，因为他们
afford to retire the way she did.
负担不起像她那样的退休生活。有
&gt;&gt; How many people could
多少人
actually save $27 a day? Because if I go
真的能一天存下27美元呢？因为如果我
back again, just over 10 years of my
回到过去，回到我人生中的那十多年
life, I mean, there's no chance I could
，我的意思是，我根本不可能
save $27 in a day. There's just no
一天存下27美元。绝对不可能，
there's just no there's no way
绝对不可能，
&gt;&gt; if you go back to what age?
如果你回到哪个年龄段？
&gt;&gt; If I go back to between
如果我回到
like 18 19 years old roughly that period
18、19岁左右，大概就是
of my life.
我人生中的那段时期。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的，
&gt;&gt; There was no way I could have save $27 a
我根本不可能一天存下27美元
day.
。
&gt;&gt; Here's really the question. Do you have
真正的问题是，你有没有
friends and do you think you have people
朋友，或者你认识的同事，
who are making more than $50,000 a year
年收入超过5万美元，却
and they're not saving $27 a day?
一天存不到27美元？
They're not even saving $10 a day. This
他们甚至连10美元都存不到。 每天。这
is true. I actually did a bit of
是真的。我实际上就此做了一些
research um on this and it says
研究，数据显示，
if we just take the United States where
如果我们只以美国为例（
I think there's what 330 million people
我认为美国大约有3.3亿人口），大约有
roughly um approximately 40 to 50
4000万到5000
million families in the US can
万个家庭能够
realistically save $27 a day. This
切实地每天节省27美元。这
represents roughly the top 30 to 35% of
大约占美国收入最高的30%到35%的
households. For everyone else, the
家庭。对于其余
bottom 65 to 70%. Saving that amount
65%到70%的家庭来说，要存下这么多钱
would require either extreme poverty
要么需要极其严格的贫困
level budgeting or is a mathematical
线预算，要么在数学上是
impossibility. over 40 million people
不可能的。他们认为有超过4000万人
they think can afford to save $27.50 a
能够负担得起每天节省27.50美元
day.
。
&gt;&gt; Yes. It's based based on income and
是的。这是基于
expenditure data from 2025 to 2026
2025年至2026年的收入和支出数据得出的结论，
approximately 40 to 50 million families
大约有4000万到5000万个
in the US can realistically save $27 a
美国家庭能够切实地每天节省27美元
day.
。
&gt;&gt; So for those 40 to 50 million people in
所以对于这4000万到5000万美国人来说，
the United States that would be
这将是
lifechanging. Now are there people who
改变人生的。当然，也有人
can't afford to say that? Absolutely. In
负担不起吗？当然有。在
the United States I I was just in uh
美国，我刚刚…… 呃，
Arizona. I just did a keynote speech. I
亚利桑那州。我刚做了一场主题演讲。我
asked the audience,
问听众，
this is when the government was shut
当时正值政府
down. I said, "How many people do you
停摆期间。我说：“你们
think in America are taking and
觉得美国有多少人正在
receiving SNAP checks?"
领取SNAP（补充营养援助计划）支票？”
&gt;&gt; What's that?
那是什么？
&gt;&gt; Thank you. Because, by the way, most
谢谢。因为，顺便说一句，大多数
Americans don't even know what a snap
美国人甚至不知道SNAP
check is. That's a check that the
支票是什么。那是
government gives to people for food. And
政府发放给民众的食品补助支票。
the dollar amounts a little over $6 a
金额略高于每天6美元
day. So, smart people in a room, by the
。所以，在座的各位聪明人，
way, I didn't know the answer to this a
顺便说一句，一周前我也不知道答案
week prior either. The answer is about
。答案是大约有
41 and a half million Americans
4150万美国人
get a snap check.
领取SNAP支票。
When I told the room that, the room
当我告诉大家这个数字时，大家都
gasped. I said, "So when you under when
倒吸了一口凉气。我说：“所以，当
you hear that the government was shut
你们听说政府
down for six weeks,
停摆了六周，
that was three pay cycles."
相当于三个工资周期的时候。”要知道
Well, the average American doesn't have
，普通美国人根本没有
two weeks of expenses set aside.
两周的开支储备。我的
I I mean, I don't think everybody fully
意思是，我认为现在并非每个人都完全
grasps the problem right now. Four out
理解这个问题。十分之
of 10 Americans can't get their hands on
四的美国人拿不出
$1,000 in case of emergency purposes. If
1000美元以备不时之需。
you actually dig into the Federal
实际上，深入研究
Reserve data, it's 37% of Americans
美联储的数据，你会发现37%的美国人
can't get their hands on $400 in case of
拿不出400美元的应急资金
emergency purposes. So, there's a whole
。所以，美国有相当
section of America that's truly
一部分人确实在苦苦挣扎
struggling. Like, but there's a whole
。事实上，还有
lot of America
很多美国人
that is still struggling. They're living
仍在苦苦挣扎。他们勉强维持
paycheck to paycheck, but their money is
生计，但因为没有理财计划，他们的钱一直在被
being taken from them all the time
消耗
because they don't have a plan for it.
。
For that bottom 60% of Americans that my
我的研究表明，对于收入最低的60%的美国人来说，他们甚至无法
$27 a day. Um, the data reveals a
每天存下27美元。数据显示，可
discretionary income cliff. Once you
支配收入存在一个断崖式下降。一旦收入
drop below the top 40% of earners, the
低于收入最高的40%，扣除
money available after bills vanishes
账单后的剩余资金就会
rapidly. The top 20% which earn I think
迅速消失。收入最高的20%的人群（我认为他们的平均家庭收入为
$96,000
9.6万美元）有
per household are in a surplus. The
盈余。
middle 20% um have a $15,000 surplus uh
中间20%的人群有1.5万美元的盈余，而
which the $27 a day takes 66% from. But
每天27美元的储蓄会消耗掉其中的66%。但收入
the bottom 40% often have a roughly
最低的40%的人群通常只有大约
$2,000 surplus. So it's impossible for
2000美元的盈余。所以，这几乎是不可能的。 为了让
them to get to the $10,000 for that
那40%的底层人群攒够1万美元，我给
What's what's the advice for them?
他们的建议是什么？从
&gt;&gt; Start with something. Okay. It's like we
小事做起。好，就像我们
took this 50 and we said cut it in half
把50美元减半，变成
25.
25美元。
I would say can you save a dollar a day?
我会问他们：你能每天存1美元吗？
I have actually talked about this idea
我其实已经用最简单的方式解释过这个想法了
really simple. Could you save $10 a day
。你能每天存10美元，
for 100 days? So like if you're
坚持100天吗？所以，如果你正在
listening to me and you happen to really
听我讲话，而且你
be struggling right now, my question
现在真的经济拮据，我的问题是：
would be could you save $10 a day for
你能每天存10美元，坚持100
100 days? Why? Because it would get you
天吗？为什么？因为这能让你
to your first $1,000 and you now have
攒够第一个1000美元，而现在
more than 50% of Americans who don't
超过50%的美国人没有
have savings. And I can't tell you how
存款。我无法告诉你，有
many people have come back after a
多少人在
hundred days and said, "Okay, I did it.
100天后回来告诉我：“我做到了！”
It wasn't easy." For some people, saving
这并不容易。对有些人来说，
$10 a day could be really really hard.
每天存下10美元真的很难。
But
但如果
you're you're into fitness. You saw my
你热爱健身，你刚才看到我
son who just came in here.
儿子了吗？
Fitness is built through daily action,
健身是通过每天的行动积累起来的，
right? It's built through daily action.
对吧？就是通过每天的行动积累起来的。
Daily eating well, going to the gym,
每天健康饮食，去健身房，
doing certain things on a regular basis.
定期做一些特定的事情。
Savings, the same thing.
存钱也是一样。
There's a company called Acorns. I
有一家叫Acorns的公司。我
invested Acorns back in 2015. Acorns
在2015年投资了Acorns。Acorns
came up with an app that helps you roll
开发了一款应用程序，可以帮助你把
your change up. So, if I go to Starbucks
零钱凑整。比如，如果我去星巴克
and I spend $9.50 on a coffee,
买了一杯9.5美元的咖啡，
you can round it up where the 50 cents
你可以把剩下的50美分存
to 10 bucks is put into investments.
到10美元，然后把这部分存起来进行投资。
Just rounding up your change.
就是把零钱凑整。
of dollars over the last 10 years by
过去10年里，人们
just rounding up their change.
仅仅通过把零钱凑整就存下了数万美元。
Every time I've tried to improve
每次我试图改善
something in my life, like my
生活中的某些方面，比如我的
businesses, my health, my relationships,
事业、我的健康、我的人际关系，
I've noticed that the biggest shifts
我都注意到，最大的改变
have come from being better informed.
来自于掌握了更多信息。
And when it comes to our health, most of
而说到我们的健康，大多数人
us know very, very little. So, when our
我们当中很多人对自身健康知之甚少。所以，当我们的
team was approached about partnering
团队接到
with function health, it felt very much
与Function Health的合作邀请时，我们觉得非常
aligned. Their team has developed a way
契合。他们的团队开发了一种全方位的
your health, many of the things that are
健康状况评估方法，
going on in your body, in the form of
通过
different tests. You do one blood draw
各种检测，让你全面了解身体的各项指标。只需一次抽血，
and it gives you access to over 160 lab
就能获得超过160项实验室检测
results. Hormones, heart health,
结果，涵盖激素水平、心脏健康、
inflammation, stress, toxins, the whole
炎症、压力、毒素等各个方面，让你一目了然
picture. I use it and so have many of my
。我自己以及我的许多
team members.
团队成员都在使用这项服务。
&gt;&gt; You sign up and you schedule your tests
注册后，你可以预约检测，
and once you're done, you get a little
完成后会收到一份
report like the one I have here. I can
类似我这份的报告。报告中可以
see my inrange results, my out of range
看到我的各项指标是否在正常范围内
results, and there's a little AI
，是否超出正常范围，还有一个人工智能
function, too. So, if I have any
功能。如果我对超出正常
questions about my out of range results,
范围的指标有任何疑问，
I can just go in there and ask it any
可以直接提问
question I want. And these tests are
。这些检测都得到了
backed by doctors and thousands of hours
医生的支持，并经过了数千小时
of research. It's $365 for a yearly
的研究。年费为365美元
membership. Go to
。访问
functionhealth.com/doac
functionhealth.com/doac，
and use the code DOAC25
并使用优惠码DOAC25即可享受优惠。
for $25 off your membership.
会员资格立减 25 美元。
I had a friend of mine contact me and I
我的一个朋友联系了我，我跟
I spoke to one of the previous financial
之前在节目中采访过的一位理财
adviserss and educators that I'd spoken
顾问兼教育工作者聊了聊
to on the show about him. He told me he
他的情况。他告诉我他
was in deep financial debt. Probably
负债累累。他
earns about £50,000 or dollars a year,
年收入大概在 5 万英镑或美元左右，
but has got himself into real debt. And
但却债台高筑。
I imagine a lot of my listeners are are
我想我的很多听众也都有
somewhat in debt, whether it's credit
不同程度的债务，无论是
card debts or loans or others. Do you
信用卡债务、贷款还是其他债务。您
have any specific advice to people that
对那些目前深陷债务泥潭的人有什么具体的建议吗
are currently straddled with debt?
？
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. Because it's one of the most
当然有。因为这是
important things you need to know how to
你必须知道如何摆脱债务的最重要的事情之一
get out of. Debt is like quicksand. Like
。债务就像流沙。就像
you know, you talked earlier about how
你之前提到的，
you were in debt and what that felt
你曾经负债累累，以及那种感觉
like. When I came out of college and I
。我大学毕业时
had $12,000 in credit card debt, it felt
背负着 1.2 万美元的信用卡债务，感觉
like the greatest weight on my
就像肩上压着千斤重担，
shoulders. Like I was carrying like a 50
就像背着一个 50
lb backpack. And how did I get out of
磅重的背包。我是怎么摆脱
debt? How do you get out of debt? I will
债务的呢？你又是如何摆脱债务的呢？我会
give you the very simple formula to
告诉你一个非常简单的公式。
getting out of debt. DolP. DolP stands
摆脱债务的关键在于“DOLP”（Done
for done on last payment. If you said to
on Last Payment）。DOLP 的意思是“最后付款完成”（Done on Last Payment）。如果你跟
me, David, I've got five credit cards.
我说：“大卫，我有五张信用卡。
cards." I'd go one, two, three, four,
”我会说：“好的，斯蒂芬，我会拿一张纸，像这样，把你的信用卡都列出来。”我会从一、二、三、四、
five. And I'd list them all. Visa,
五开始，把它们全部列出来。Visa、
Mastercard,
万事达卡，
and I'd list them. And then I want to
我都会列出来。然后我想
know, Steve, how much do you owe? So, I
知道，斯蒂芬，你欠了多少钱？所以，我
put the dollar amount down. And what I
会把金额写下来。
would do is I put the dollar amount down
我会把金额写
on paper and I list it small
在纸上，从小
to large.
到大排列。
Then I want to know the interest rate.
然后我想知道利率。
Now, what people say is, "Oh, you should
现在，人们常说：“你应该
it off first." But I wouldn't tell you
先还清利率最高的信用卡。”但我不会这么建议你
that, Stephen.
，斯蒂芬。
I'd tell you you take the smallest
我会告诉你，先还清金额最小的
credit card. I don't care what the
信用卡。我不在乎
interest rate is.
利率是多少。
&gt;&gt; The smallest amount.
金额最小的。
&gt;&gt; Smallest amount. So maybe this card
最小的金额。比如这张卡欠款
right here is $500. And this card down
500 美元。这张卡欠款……
here is 3,000.
3000。
I'd have you make minimum payments on
我会让你
every card
每张卡都
automatically. This is really important,
自动支付最低还款额。这一点非常重要，就是
the automatic part. Have you go on I'd
自动还款。
literally go into your house. I'd open
我会亲自去你家，
up the I'd open up your iPad and I'd
打开你的iPad，让
have you make minimum payments online
你在线自动支付最低还款额，
automatically so that every card's paid
确保每张卡都能
on time. Then I'd say, "Stephen, how
按时还款。然后我会问你：“斯蒂芬，
much extra money do you have?" Because I
你还剩多少钱？”因为我
want you to put it all towards the
想让你把所有钱都用来还欠款额
smallest card. We're going to get that
最小的那张卡。我们要
small card paid off as fast as possible.
尽快还清这张卡的欠款。
We're going to add all the extra money
我们会把所有多余的钱都加到
to that small card. Minimum payments on
这张卡上，只还最低还款额
everything. Once that card's paid off,
。一旦这张卡还清了，
we're going to go like this. You don't
我们就会这样做。你
have to close the account because we
不需要销户，因为我们
don't want to lower your credit score,
不想降低你的信用评分，
but we're going to put that card over
但我们会把这张卡放到一边，永远
here. never use it. Now, we're going to
不要再用它。现在，我们要
go to the next next smallest card.
开始还欠款额次小的那张卡了。
Some people call this the snowball
有些人把这叫做“滚雪球”
approach.
策略。
The reason I teach this system is it
我教你这套方法的原因在于，它可以
have as fast as possible.
尽快减少你拥有的信用卡数量。
And you see yourself make progress. It's
你看，你 取得进展。在
financially.
财务方面，看到自己取得进步至关重要。
Then I would attack the interest rates
接下来，我会着手降低利率，
because the interest rates aren't always
因为利率并非
permanent. You can negotiate your rates
一成不变。你可以协商
lower. You can move credit cards to
降低利率，也可以将信用卡转移到
another card with a low interest rate.
利率较低的卡上。
Have to be very careful though when you
但这样做时务必非常谨慎，
do that because they're waiting for you
因为发卡机构会等着你犯错，比如
to make a slip up and make a late
逾期
payment. And when they do, they'll jack
还款。一旦发生这种情况，他们就会立即
the credit card interest rates back up
提高信用卡利率
again.
。
companies if you're really struggling
如果你真的遇到了困难，也可以打电话给信用卡公司，
and tell them, "I'm struggling and I'd
告诉他们：“我遇到了困难，
like to know if you have a program in
想了解一下你们是否有
place where I can stop the interest rate
可以暂停利息、帮助我还清欠款
and pay these cards off and more
并降低还款额度的项目
accessible." Like this is basically what
。” 这基本上就是
the nonprofit credit card counseling
非营利性信用卡咨询
organizations do. But the credit card
机构的工作内容。但信用卡
companies often have programs too for
公司通常也有类似的计划
this. They'll tell you to stop using the
。他们会建议你停止使用
card. they'll actually make it so you
信用卡，甚至会让你
can't use the card anymore, but they'll
无法再使用，但会
stop the interest rate. So, that
暂停收取利息。这种
approach has helped so many people get
方法已经帮助很多人
out of credit card debt.
摆脱了信用​​卡债务。
Now, I just want to say something super
现在，我只想…… 我要说一些非常
important because I've gone through
重要的话，因为我经历过
this.
这一切。
When you go through the work of getting
当你努力
out of credit card debt,
摆脱信用卡债务时，
it's a huge victory.
那真是一场巨大的胜利。
Don't go out and celebrate
千万不要因为庆祝而
on the credit cards because I got myself
刷爆信用卡，因为我
out of credit card debt in college,
大学三年级的时候就还清了信用卡债务，结果
celebrated and got myself back into
庆祝之后又重新欠了
credit card debt.
债。很多
&gt;&gt; And people do this all the time. Usually
人都会重蹈覆辙。通常
people get themselves in a hole at least
人们至少会陷入债务泥潭
twice, sometimes three times.
两次，有时甚至三次。千万
Don't go back in a hole again. Uh I
不要再重蹈覆辙。我
didn't carry credit cards for 30 years.
30年来都没用过信用卡，
I only carried a debit card and I had to
只用借记卡，而且
pay it off every month. Should these
每个月都要还款。那些
people um who are in the bottom sort of
处于社会底层
60% be thinking at all about how to make
60%的人，是否应该考虑如何赚
more money, how to increase their
更多钱，如何增加
income?
收入呢？
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. And what are the like the
当然应该。那么，
recommend just from your own experience
根据你自身的职业经验，
world and
以及
&gt;&gt; so my experience and I know that you
我的经验，你认为最简单的方法是什么呢？我知道
look you wrote this great book diary of
你写了一本很棒的书，《
a CEO right anybody hasn't read your
CEO日记》，对吧？还没读过你的
book you have this great book what's the
书的人肯定都看过。你觉得最好的方法是什么？
best way to grow your income if you have
如果你有工作，想要增加收入，关键在于把工作
a job it's to be good at what you do
做好。
right you can have a job at minimum wage
你可以做一份最低工资的工作，
let's pretend you work at McDonald's and
比如说你在麦当劳工作，
you have a job working minimum wage
拿着最低工资
McDonald's. The owner of McDonald's, the
。麦当劳的老板，
guy who owns that franchise or the gal
或者说
that owns that franchise desperately
这家加盟店的老板娘，非常
needs good employees. Who becomes a
需要优秀的员工。那么，谁能晋升为
manager that makes more money? The
经理，赚更多的钱呢？当然是那些
person who works really well. Now, a lot
工作表现出色的人。现在，很多
of people, I don't I don't know if I
人，比如我，都不确定自己是否
want to work McDonald's. I'm just giving
想在麦当劳工作。我只是举个
it as an example. Anywhere you work, how
例子。无论你在哪里工作，想要
you grow your income is you are the best
提高收入，关键在于你要
at what you do. You show up early. You
做到最好。你要早到，
have a game plan at work. You work late.
工作时要有计划，工作到很晚，
You do what you say you're going to do.
说到做到，
You don't wait to be told what to do,
不要等着别人告诉你该做什么，
right? Like I've been an entrepreneur
对吧？我这
all my lifetime. The hardest thing about
辈子都在创业。
being an entrepreneur is what?
创业最难的是什么？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
没错，
&gt;&gt; Everything. [laughter]
所有的一切。[笑声] 真的
&gt;&gt; It's everything. And most people are
是所有的一切。而且大多数人……
entrepreneurs go, "Well, it's, you know,
企业家们会说：“你知道，
a lot of times it's hard to have good
很多时候，
people unless you're a good leader."
除非你是一位优秀的领导者，否则很难找到优秀的人才。”
People are so thirsty to have jobs with
人们渴望找到
purpose and meaning. And most people are
有意义、有价值工作。而且大多数人
actually looking for leadership.
实际上都在寻找领导者。
So if you can be really good at what you
所以，如果你能真正精通你的工作
do, you will make more money. There's no
，你就能赚到更多钱。
limit to wealth in the world, right?
世界上的财富是没有上限的，对吧？
Like we've never seen so much wealth
就像我们一生中从未见过像现在这样多的财富
being created in our entire lives as
被创造出来一样
right now. If I were young, a lot of
。如果我年轻，很多
people, well, you should learn AI.
人会说，你应该学习人工智能。
Yeah, you know what? Probably you
是的，你知道吗？你
definitely should learn how to use AI
肯定应该学习如何使用人工智能，
because if you don't learn how to use
因为如果你不学习如何使用
AI, you're going to have really limited
人工智能，你的技能就会非常有限，只能
skills and go the and do certain jobs.
从事某些特定的工作。
You know what else people are going to
你知道人们还会
go out and do? Learn how to be a
去做什么吗？学习如何当
plumber. Learn how to be electrician.
水管工。学习如何当电工。
Learn how to put up garage doors. I've
学习如何安装车库门。我
got friends. I got I was just recently
有一些朋友。我最近刚
on a podcast with a guy who's made a
和一位靠安装车库门赚了十亿美元的人一起参加了一个播客节目
billion dollars putting in garage doors.
。
&gt;&gt; And he took me through his warehouse and
他带我参观了他的仓库，并向
showed me their garage door models. And
我展示了他们的…… 车库门模型。然后
I was like, you know, I've got a friend
我就想，你知道，我有个朋友是
who makes gyms that go in garages. I
做车库健身房的。我
just connected them. He's got a huge
就把他们联系起来了。他
business making gyms for garages.
做车库健身房的生意非常红火。机会真的
There's just no limit to the amount of
无穷无尽。不过，
opportunities out there. You have to
你必须摆脱
though get out of a stuck mind frame. I
思维定势。我的
mean, you had Tony Robbins here. If
意思是，托尼·罗宾斯也来过。如果说
there's anybody who can help you get out
有人能帮你摆脱
of a stuck mind frame, it's that guy,
思维定势，那肯定是他，对
right? But you can't you can't have they
吧？但你不能，你不能像
Zig Ziggler used to call it stinking
齐格·齐格勒说的那样，陷入“糟糕的
thinking. You have to have
思维”。你必须有
the ability to look into the future and
能力展望未来，并
believe that your future can be as
相信你的未来可以像
exciting today or better. I put up a
今天一样精彩，甚至更好。我昨天发了一篇
post yesterday. I said, um, I would
帖子。我说，嗯，我
rather be an optimist and be wrong than
宁愿做一个乐观主义者，即使错了，也不愿做
a pessimist and be right.
一个悲观主义者，即使对了。
And you show me somebody who wants to
你给我找一个想赚
make more money, go into the world an
更多钱的人，让他带着
optimist and figure out how to go make
乐观的心态去想办法
more money.
赚钱。
Do you think a lot of this is a mindset
你觉得这一切的核心是不是在于心态
at at at the core of it? Obviously there
？当然，也
are real socioeconomic factors and
存在一些真正的社会经济因素。 有很多因素，
there's people live in certain
人们生活在特定的
situations and if I think back to you
环境中。回想
know where I was born in Botswana
我的出生地博茨瓦纳，
there's just less opportunity and
那里机会较少，
sometimes you have repressive
有时还会面临压制性的
governments and other factors that will
政府和其他一些客观因素，这些都会
objectively keep you stuck but all other
让你停滞不前。但即便其他
things being equal
条件相同，
how much of the game is mindset.
心态也至关重要。最终，一切都
&gt;&gt; It always comes down to a decision and
取决于一个决定。
we started by talking about my
我们一开始就聊到了我的
grandmother. If my grandmother hadn't
祖母。如果我祖母没有
made a decision at 30 that she didn't
在30岁时下定决心不再
want to be poor, she was tired of living
贫穷，不再忍受月光族的生活
paycheck to paycheck. If she hadn't
，如果她没有
decided that she would go out and teach
决定自学
herself about money and take 50 cents of
理财，并从自己的
her paycheck and 50 cents from my
工资和
grandfather's paycheck and start
祖父的工资中各拿出50美分开始
investing,
投资，
I wouldn't be here today. She made a
我今天就不会站在这里。她的这个
decision that had a ripple effect
决定
through our family. She built financial
对我们整个家庭产生了连锁反应。她
security for herself with that one
凭借这个决定为自己建立了经济保障
decision.
。
She taught my father how to invest and
她教会了我的父亲如何投资，
he was a financial adviser for over 45
他做了45多年的财务顾问
years. My sister's a financial adviser.
。我的姐姐也是一名财务顾问。
I was a financial adviser. I spent the
我也曾是一名财务顾问。在
last 30 years teaching people about
过去的30年里，我一直在教人们如何
money. One woman's decision had this
理财。 这位女士的决定产生了
ripple effect. So, one thing I say to
连锁反应。所以，我想对所有
people who are listening, especially the
听众，特别是
moms,
妈妈们说，
sometimes you got to make
有时候你必须做出
[clears throat] a decision that's not
一个
just for you.
不仅仅为了你自己的决定。
You're actually making a decision for
你实际上是在为
your family. and you can come up with a
你的家人做决定。你可以列出一堆
list of reasons why this stuff won't
理由来说明为什么这些事情
work. Somebody who's watching this show
行不通。现在正在观看
or listening to us right now, they're
或收听我们节目的人，他们
already interested in this. That's why
已经对此感兴趣了。这就是
they're here. Now, they're here for a
他们来这里的原因。他们来这里的
couple reasons. Either A, they're
原因有两个。要么是A，他们
hurting financially and they know they
经济拮据，知道自己
need to fix something. Great. Start
需要做出改变。很好。那就从
where you are. Fix what needs to be
你现在的情况开始。解决需要
fixed. Some people are like, you know, I
解决的问题。有些人会说，你知道，我
think I'm doing pretty well, but I'm not
觉得我做得还不错，但我
sure if I'm doing everything well. you
不确定我是否事事都做得好。你
know, I I've I've opened up my Roth IRA
知道，我开了罗斯个人退休账户（Roth IRA）
or I've opened up my 401k plan. I'm
或者401k计划。我在
putting some money away, but I don't
存钱，但我不
know if I'm putting enough money away.
知道我存的钱够不够。
Then you can improve what you're doing.
然后你可以改进…… 你现在正在做什么？
Some people like, I'm renting. I think I
有些人就像，我现在租房。我想有
would like to buy a house someday. All
一天能买房。
right, make that a goal. I teach three
好，那就把这作为目标。关于理财，我提倡“三
buckets when it comes to money. Three
桶”的概念。三个“
baskets. Pay yourself first for
篮子”。首先要给自己存钱，用于
retirement. We haven't even talked about
退休。我们还没谈到
emergencies yet. Putting aside putting
紧急情况呢。要预留
aside money for emergency purposes. Have
应急资金。
to talk about that. You got to you got
这必须得说说。你必须
to get more money put aside for
为紧急情况预留更多资金，
emergency purposes and then building a
然后建立一个
dream account. You need to put money
梦想账户。你需要
away for your dreams. Those three
为你的梦想存钱。这三个
accounts should be automated.
账户应该设置自动化。
&gt;&gt; And on that point of having three
说到这三个
accounts, you call it a future account,
账户，你可以把它们叫做未来账户、
an emergency account, and a dream
应急账户和梦想
account. How much of your earnings
账户。那么，
should you be putting into each of those
你每个月应该把多少收入存入每个
accounts on a monthly basis?
账户呢？
&gt;&gt; All right. So, keep it super simple. I
好。所以，尽量简单。我
recommend one hour a day. Again, said
建议每天存一个小时。就像我
this earlier, it's 12 and a half% of
之前说的，这是
your gross income. When you say 1 hour a
你总收入的12.5%。你说每天存一个小时
day, you mean one hour of the the time
，是指
you work per day.
你每天工作时间中的一个小时。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, whatever you make an hour.
是的。所以，无论你每小时赚多少钱。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; It's if you're say if if you're working
如果你…… 假设你
a 40hour work week, 12 and a half% of
每周工作40小时，
your gross income goes off the top into
你总收入的12.5%会直接存入
a retirement account. Now, let me just
退休账户。现在，我要
say something up for the yahutters.
对那些“傻瓜”说几句。
They're like, I can't go from 0 to 12%.
他们会说，我不可能一下子从0%直接存到12%。
There's no way. Then start at 1%.
这根本不可能。那就从1%开始吧。
If you're not saving right now and
如果你现在没有储蓄，而
you're listening to us and all you do
你正在听我们的节目，那么
when you leave this podcast is make one
在你离开这个播客后，你只需要做一个
decision
决定：
and that decision is I'm going to save
我要把
1% of my income and you start that this
收入的1%存起来。如果你从这个
month your life will change. Your life
月开始就这么做，你的生活将会发生改变。你的生活
will change because you start the
会改变，因为你开始了
process of making a difference. It's
改变的进程。这就像
just like the first day you go to the
你第一天去
gym. Now I will tell you if you save 1%
健身房一样。我告诉你，如果你把收入的1%存起来，
of your income you won't notice it. And
你不会感觉到任何变化。但
if you did that every month for a year,
如果你每个月都这样做，坚持一年，
at the end of the year, you would have
到年底你就能
saved 12% and you will be saving four
存下12%，这将是
times what the average American saves
普通美国人储蓄额的四倍，而且
and you will be in a rockstar shape.
你的生活会变得非常精彩。
Then the second hour, this is where
接下来是第二小时，这是
people's minds blow up. But the second
人们…… 脑洞大开。但是第二个
hour, so the first hour goes for the
小时，也就是第一个小时用来规划
future, the second hour goes for safety
未来，第二个小时用来保障安全
and for dreams. So 30 minutes of your
和追逐梦想。所以，你收入的30分钟
income, roughly 5%
，大约5%
should go into an emergency account and
应该存入应急账户，
another 5% goes into a dream account.
另外5%存入梦想账户。
Now, that dream account could be for
这个梦想账户可以用来
buying a house, could be saving money
买房，可以用来攒
for college, could be the vacation you
大学学费，可以用来
want to take at the end of the year,
支付年底的度假费用，
could be getting married, could be the
可以用来结婚，可以用来买
engagement ring, but you're putting
订婚戒指，总之，你是在
money away for your dreams. Because when
为你的梦想存钱。因为当
you put money away for your dreams,
你为梦想存钱时，
that's how they become real.
它们就会变成现实。
&gt;&gt; And you know, the book is called The
你知道，这本书叫《
Automatic Millionaire. This is a book
自动百万富翁》。这本书本身就
that sold over two million copies
卖出了超过两百万册
&gt;&gt; um on its own.
。
Why did you use the word automatic?
你为什么用“自动”这个词？
&gt;&gt; Unless your financial plan is automatic,
除非你的理财计划是自动的，否则
it will fail.
它就会失败。
How do I know this? Because I spent nine
我怎么知道的？因为我
years as a financial adviser at Morgan
在摩根士丹利做了九年的财务顾问，
Stanley and I got to see firsthand.
我亲眼目睹了这一切。
Everyone who came into my office with an
所有来我办公室的
ordinary income who built wealth, they
普通收入者，他们都是
did it by saving automatically.
通过自动储蓄积累财富的。
Every single time a client came into my
每次有客户来我
office and they said, "I'm going to
办公室，他们都会说，  “我会亲自
bring you a check every month myself." I
每月给你寄支票。” 我的
never had a client save for more than
客户从来没有存过超过
six months. They stopped.
六个月的钱。他们都放弃了。
When it once you make the decision to
一旦你决定让
automate your financial life, it works
你的财务生活自动化，它就会
in the background.
在后台自动运行。
Now, here's the thing. Everybody else is
现在，关键在于，其他人
already doing this to you.
已经在这么做了。
You go sign, you go to go to a gym to go
你去签合同，去健身房
work out. They don't ask you to bring
锻炼。他们不会要求你
them money every month. They
每月给他们钱。他们会
automatically bill you. You get a phone
自动向你收费。你收到电话
bill, they automatically bill you.
账单，也是自动扣款。
Today, in many cases, when you rent,
如今，在很多情况下，当你租房时，他们会自动从你的账户里扣款。
your account. The banks automatically
银行会自动从你的账户里扣除
take money from you for your mortgage.
你的房贷。
When you pay taxes, they're all
你缴税的时候，一切都是
automated. Everyone takes money from you
自动的。每个人都在自动地从你身上扣钱
automatically. Everything that you sign
。你
up for on your phone is a subscription
在手机上注册的所有东西都是订阅
service. Netflix, go through your credit
服务。Netflix，看看你
card today. Open up your phone, look at
今天的信用卡账单。打开你的手机，看看
all your subscriptions. All those
你所有的订阅项目。所有这些
businesses are taking money from you
公司都在自动地从你身上扣钱
automatically. Why? That's the only way
。为什么？因为这是
they can be in business. They know if
他们维持运营的唯一方式。他们知道，如果
they don't get money from you
他们不能自动从你身上扣款
automatically, you won't keep using
，你就不会继续使用
them. Most people who start off with a
他们的服务。大多数人一开始……
free subscription, it'll take them three
免费订阅的话，用户可能需要三
to six months to turn off something that
到六个月的时间才能取消一些
they don't use.
不用的服务。
I'm here getting people to automate
我在这里的目标是帮助大家实现
their financial life for themselves.
财务生活的自动化。
Is there simple ways, apps, tools,
有没有什么简单的方法、应用、工具或
websites we can use to go through all of
网站，可以帮助我们浏览
our subscriptions and turn them all off?
并关闭所有订阅呢？
&gt;&gt; Yes, there are. So, let me tell you the
答案是肯定的。让我来告诉你
easiest way. This is really actually
最简单的方法。这其实是
free publicity for Apple, okay? Because
给苹果的免费宣传，好吗？因为
so many people have Apple phones. Number
很多人都用苹果手机。
one, only do your subscriptions inside
首先，所有订阅都只在苹果应用内进行
of Apple. In an ideal world, don't pay
。理想情况下，不要
anybody directly. Do it all through
直接向任何人付费。所有订阅都通过
Apple.
苹果应用完成。
&gt;&gt; Why? Because if you go to the bottom of
为什么呢？因为如果你
your phone and you don't know how to do
不知道怎么操作，可以点击手机底部的“
this and you put subscriptions,
订阅”选项，它
up will pop everything that you've
会弹出你
signed up for and you can go click click
订阅的所有项目，然后你可以点击、点击、点击，
click and turn them all off.
把它们全部关闭。
&gt;&gt; Do that.
就这么做。
&gt;&gt; Another thing I will tell you is that
还有一点要告诉你，
when you sign up for anything, let's say
当你订阅任何东西时，
it's a one year because everything now
比如现在很多都是
is a one-year trial subscription or a
一年或
one month trial subscription.
一个月的试用期，注册后立刻
off. Because what happens is if you sign
关闭。因为如果你……
up for anything and think of any
注册任何东西，想想
subscription you can imagine. Companies
你能想到的任何订阅服务。公司肯定
hate me for this. The moment you shut it
恨死我了。一旦你取消订阅，
renew, they will offer you a better deal
续订的时候，他们就会给你提供更优惠的
to renew.
续订价格。
&gt;&gt; Okay, so I've opened up my phone. I've
好了，我打开手机，
gone to the settings. I've clicked on my
进入设置，点击我的
name in the settings and then I've
名字，然后
clicked on the button subscriptions.
点击“订阅”按钮。
I have one, two, three, four, five, six,
我这里有1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9、10、11个订阅，
seven, eight, nine, 10, 11 of which
其中
[laughter]
[笑]
three of them
三个
I would keep.
我会保留。
So, all these other ones have just been
其他的订阅都一直在
running in the background and and it's
后台运行，
because I used an app one time and it
因为我之前用过一个应用，它给
signed me up to some kind of free trial
我注册了一个免费试用，
and I just totally forgot to cancel it.
但我完全忘记取消了。
So, I've got Oh my god, some of them are
所以，我的天哪，有些订阅简直多到爆炸
massive.
。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, so as you do this, what you're
好了。你
doing right now is a real life example.
现在做的，就是一个真实的例子。
So, if someone's listening to us,
如果有人正在听我们说话，或者
watching this, they're married, they've
看这个视频，他们可能是已婚人士、
got kids, or they're single by
有孩子，或者单身人士，那么…… 就他们
themselves,
自身而言，
this one exercise, my guess is there are
我猜想，
many, many people listening that could
很多听众都能
find $50, $100, $200 a month that they
找到每月节省 50、100 甚至 200 美元的方法，将这
could shut off and redirect that money
笔钱
to saving and investing and that could
用于储蓄和投资，这或许
change their life. Are there other apps
能改变他们的人生。有没有其他应用程序
you can use and go to to figure out how
可以用来
to cancel or leave your subscription?
取消或终止订阅呢？确实
&gt;&gt; So there there are and most these apps
有，但大多数这类应用程序都
you have to pay for, right? So like you
需要付费，对吧？比如，你
can go to So then you're right back into
可以使用……这样一来，你又得花钱买
paying for an app now. Probably the two
应用程序了。
popular most popular apps are Monarch
最受欢迎的两款应用程序可能是 Monarch
and Ynab. You can also do this with your
和 Ynab。你也可以用
credit cards. Um the credit card comes
信用卡来操作。信用卡
statements. And again, I go back to the
账单上的显示效果更好。我再次以
Apple example because Apple makes it the
苹果为例，因为苹果让
easiest to shut these off.
取消订阅变得最简单。
&gt;&gt; Maybe some of you will be spending $100
也许你们有些人每月要花 100 美元
a month. So, I did $100 a month. And it
。所以我假设每月 100 美元。数据
says if you invest if you sort of cancel
显示，如果你取消
those subscriptions and invest $100 per
这些订阅，每月投资 100 美元，持续
month for 40 years, an annual rate of
40 年，年
return of about 10%, which is roughly
回报率约为 10%，这和你……的收益大致相同。
some of the big tech index funds at the
目前，你可以把钱投到一些大型科技指数基金里
moment. The total money you'll have in
。40年后，你的总资产将达到
40 years is $632,000,
63.2万美元，这笔
amount of money.
钱足以改变你的人生，令人震惊。真的非常
&gt;&gt; It's staggering. And let me just give
惊人。接下来，我想推荐
some very specific investment for people
一些具体的投资项目供大家
to consider, right? And they still need
参考，对吧？当然，大家仍然需要
to do their own due diligence and read
自行进行尽职调查，阅读
perspectuses. And yes, there's risk
相关报告。没错，
involved in the stock market. But the
股市投资是有风险的。但
first one I would talk about and look
我首先要介绍的
at, and these are all listed in my book
，也是我书中列出的，是
because I just want to give because
因为我只是想让大家了解一下，因为很多
people like, what's an index fund? What
人可能会问：什么是指数基金？
do I buy? Look at the Vanguard Total
我应该买什么？不妨看看先锋集团全
Stock Market Fund. The symbol is VTI.
股票市场基金（Vanguard Total Stock Market Fund）。 该符号为VTI。
Okay, this this is actually the largest
好的，这实际上是世界上最大的
index fund in the world. There's
指数基金。
trillions of dollars now in this fund. I
这个基金现在有数万亿美元。 我
talk about it in the book. I looked up
在书中谈到了这件事。 我查了一下
the annual uh the annual returns of VTI
VTI
the last 10 years have been 14%.
过去10年的年收益率，平均为14%。
14% annually. This fund has 3500
每年增长14%。 该基金持有3500只
stocks. You you know all the biggest US
股票。 你了解所有美国最大的
stocks. So you don't have to figure out
股票。 所以你不用费心去想该
what stock to buy. You buy this fund,
买哪只股票了。 购买这只基金，也就是
you buy an exchange traded mutual fund,
购买一只交易所交易的共同基金，
you have access to 3,500 great American
您就可以投资 3500 家优秀的美国
companies. I'll give you another stock
公司。 我再给你推荐一只股票
index fund. I love
指数基金。 我非常喜欢这款产品，
&gt;&gt; and everybody can buy this on their
而且现在几乎每个人都能通过手机购买到它
&gt;&gt; literally. You can go to Vanguard,
。 你可以去先锋集团、
Schwab, Fidelity. This funds, this is an
嘉信理财、富达投资。 这只基金是
ETF, so it's available everywhere. It's
ETF，所以到处都能买到。 这是
a stock. And if you want to figure out
一支股票。 如果你想弄清楚
how to do this and you're listening
如何操作，而且你现在正在收听
right now, what I'd do is use ChatV or
，我的建议是使用 ChatV 或
Gemini and put in the stock the the fund
Gemini，输入刚才
that um has been said and ask it how do
提到的基金股票，然后问它“在
I invest in this in the country that I'm
我所在的国家，我该如何投资这个基金
in? What app do I need to use? What
？” 我需要使用哪个应用程序？
website do I need to use? Again, this is
我需要使用哪个网站？ 再次声明，这
not investment advice. Well, I guess it
并非投资建议。 嗯，
kind of sounds like it is, but
听起来好像是这样，但是
&gt;&gt; Well, and but it's also like so like if
，而且，就像如果
someone says, "Okay, but I'm not I'm in
有人说：“好吧，但我现在不在英国
um wherever I am. I'm in the UK. What's
。我在英国。那么，
an index fund in the UK that covers the
英国有哪些涵盖英国的指数基金呢
UK?" I'll give you the global version of
？” 我会给你VTI的全球版本
VTI. So, because I own these funds, so I
。 所以，因为我持有这些基金，
So, the global version of VTI is a
所以，VTI 的全球版本是一个
symbol which is all I'm going to give
符号，这就是我要给
you another Vanguard fund.
你介绍的另一个 Vanguard 基金。
&gt;&gt; When you say you own these funds, for
您说您拥有这些资金，为了
clarity, you mean you've invested in
明确起见，您的意思是您已经投资了
them?
这些资金吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I've got money in these mutual
是的，我投资了一些共同
funds. So, this other fund because I
基金。 所以，我还有另一笔基金，因为我
have I want money my my personal money
有一些钱，我想把我的个人资金投入到
that's in the stock market. I am
股市中。 我的投资组合中，
one-third global investments and I'm
三分之一是全球投资，
twothirds US investments.
三分之二是美国投资。
So, I have a lot of global index funds.
所以我持有大量全球指数基金。
This global index fund the symbol is Va.
这只全球指数基金的代码是Va。
Okay. So this is the Vanguard global
好的。 所以这是
index fund without US stock. Symbol
不包含美国股票的先锋全球指数基金。 符号
again is VA.
仍然是VA。
That fund last year and it won't always
去年该基金的表现如此，但这种情况不会一直持续下去，
be like this because global investments
因为全球投资
have underperformed the US for a long
长期以来一直逊于美国投资
period of time. That fund last year was
。 该基金去年
up 35%.
上涨了35%。
Last year, global investments
去年，全球投资
significantly outperformed the US
表现显著优于美国
investments and the US investment market
投资，而美国投资市场
was up on average of 17%. So the US
平均上涨了 17%。 因此，美国
markets were up 17% or higher and global
股市上涨了17%或更多，全球
investments were up 30% or higher. Now
投资上涨了30%或更多。
there will be a point in time, Stephen,
史蒂芬，
without a shadow of a doubt that we will
毫无疑问，
see a market pullback. And when that day
市场终将出现回调。 当那一天
comes, you have to stay the course and
到来时，你必须坚持下去，
keep investing automatically monthly.
继续每月自动投资。
And then I'm going to give you a tech
然后我会向你推荐一个科技
fund because everybody wants to know
基金，因为每个人都想知道
what should I invest in that is, you
我应该投资什么，也就是说
know, should I invest in an AI tech
，我应该投资人工智能科技
fund? And my answer would be is you
基金吗？ 我的答案是，你
don't need an AI tech fund. You need the
不需要人工智能技术基金。 你需要
best tech fund that's existed in my
我这辈子见过的最好的科技基金
lifetime. And that's the NASDAQ 100 ETF.
。 这就是纳斯达克100指数ETF。
The symbol for that is QQQ.
它的符号是 QQQ。
So go and look up, you know, go into
所以，去查一下，你知道，用
whatever you're using and go look up
你正在使用的任何工具，去查一下
QQQ, read about the top 100 stocks in
QQQ，看看纳斯达克前 100 只股票
the NASDAQ and the returns for QQQ. I
以及 QQQ 的收益情况。 我的
mean, actually, in the top of my mind
意思是，实际上，我
right now, I can I think it's over 20%.
现在脑海里立刻浮现出一个想法，我认为它超过 20%。
Um, but look up what has the QQQ total
嗯，查一下
return been for the last 10 years.
过去 10 年 QQQ 的总回报率是多少。
I can tell you since I put money in QQQ,
我可以告诉你，自从我投资了QQQ以来，
it's gone up tenfold. Now, the market's
它已经上涨了十倍。 现在市场行情令人
been unbelievable and there will be
难以置信，
pullbacks. And that is also why I should
回调在所难免。 这也是我为什么
say this, Stephen, because we haven't
要说这些的原因，斯蒂芬，因为我们还没有
even addressed this. I don't run around
讨论过这个问题。 我不会到处
telling people to put all their money in
劝别人把所有的钱都投入
the stock market. I also don't think
股市。 我也不认为
that young people should be putting all
年轻人应该把所有的
their money in the stock market. I think
钱都投入股市。 我认为
one of the greatest myths out there is
最大的误区之一就是
that when you're young, you should take
年轻的时候应该去
a lot of risk. Let me say that one more
冒险。 让我再说一遍，
time because it's super important. So,
因为这非常重要。 所以，一定要让它
make sure it sits.
静置。
Everyone says when you're young, you
人人都说年轻的时候
should take risk.
应该冒险。
The problem with that advice is that
这种建议的问题在于，
today people in their 20s and their 30s
如今二三十岁的人都
are taking a lot of risk. They're not
在承担很多风险。 他们不
just putting money in index funds.
只是把钱投到指数基金里。
They're putting money in meme coins.
他们把钱投进了表情包币里。
They're putting money in meme stocks.
他们正在投资网络迷因股票。
They're putting money in NFTTS.
他们正在投资NFTTS。
They're on social media and Tik Tok
他们在社交媒体和抖音上
watching people day trade. They're
观看人们进行日内交易。 他们正
trying to get into options. What they're
试图获得期权。 他们
really trying to do is get rich quick.
真正想做的其实是快速致富。
All I can tell you is the older guy in
我只能告诉在场的这位年纪较大的人
the room here, people who try to get
，那些想
rich quick stay broke forever. And the
快速致富的人最终都会一贫如洗。
your money when you're young is if you
年轻时用钱承担过多风险的问题在于，
keep if you do everything right, like
即使你一切都做得很好，比如说
let's just say you're the you shut off
你取消了
all your subscriptions and you're saving
所有订阅服务，
$200 a month, but you put that $200 a
每月节省了 200 美元，但你把这 200 美元投入
month into a junk investment and you
到垃圾投资中，
turn around in 10 years and you have
10 年后你却
nothing to show for it, you'll stop
一无所获，你就会停止
investing.
投资。
&gt;&gt; Looking at the QQQ data, so this is the
看一下 QQQ 的数据，这是
NASDAQ 100. So this invests in the top
纳斯达克 100 指数。该指数投资于美国排名前
100 companies in America. in the NASDAQ
100 的公司。 在纳斯达克
stock exchange.
股票交易所上市。
&gt;&gt; The returns over the last 10 years from
从
2016 to 2026, the annualized returns
2016 年到 2026 年的过去 10 年，年化收益率
have been roughly 19%.
约为 19%。
The total return over that period has
该期间的总回报率
been roughly 480%.
约为 480%。
So, a $10,000 investment 10 years ago
所以，如果你10年前投资了1万美元，而当时什么
today if you'd done nothing.
都没做，那么现在这笔投资的价值大约是6万美元。
&gt;&gt; Then nothing
之后就再也没有
&gt;&gt; ever added to it. Over the last 20
添加过任何东西。 过去 20
years, the annualized returns, the
年的年化
return every year has been 15% with a
收益率为 15%，
total return over that period of 1,500%.
在此期间的总收益率为 1500%。   再说一遍
And again, so if you've added $10,000 to
，如果你在 20 年前投入了 1 万美元，之后什么
it 20 years ago and done nothing, you
都没做，那么今天你
would have roughly $170,000
大约会有 17 万美元
today.
。   这就是
&gt;&gt; So here's the beauty of what you just
你刚才
did. You checked my my you checked my
所做事情的妙处所在。 你查看了我的
advice. You looked at the data and now
建议。 你已经查看了数据，现在
you know what has been done in the past,
你知道过去都做了些什么，
right? Let me give you a super boring
对吧？ 让我给你介绍一个超级无聊的
fund. I'm not sponsored by Vanguard. I'm
基金。 我没有接受先锋集团的赞助。 我
just giving generic vanilla stuff here.
这里只是提供一些普通的参考资料。
Look up the Vanguard balanced fund. So,
查一下先锋平衡基金。 没错，就是
right, Vanguard Balanced Fund. And the
先锋平衡基金。
Vanguard Balance Fund is 60% stocks and
先锋平衡基金的投资组合中，股票占比60%，
40% bonds. That by the way is the most
债券占比40%。 顺便一提，这是最
typical asset allocation. The difference
典型的资产配置方式。
between stocks and bonds in the world.
世界上的股票和债券之间的区别。
The average retiree has a portfolio
一般退休人员的投资组合中，
that's about 60% stock and 40% bonds.
股票占比约为 60%，债券占比约为 40%。
You look up the Valangard balance fund
你查阅一下Valangard平衡基金，
and what you're going to find is that
就会发现该
fund has averaged over 8% annually since
基金自成立以来年均收益率超过8%
inception.
。
It is as boring an investment as they
这是最乏味的投资之一
come. So if someone says, "Well, I don't
。 所以如果有人说：“我
want to be 100% stocks. I just want to
不想100%投资股票。我只想
be I want to be more conservative, but I
更保守一些，但
want some stock exposure. The Vanguard
又想配置一些股票。”先锋
balance fund is a great example.
平衡基金就是一个很好的例子。
I list all these funds in the automatic
我在《自动百万富翁》这本书里列出了所有这些基金
millionaire. One of the kind of funds I
。我
talk about the most is what's called a
最常谈到的一种基金是
targetdated mutual fund. I don't know if
目标日期共同基金。我不知道
you guys have you guys have a 401k plan.
你们有没有401k计划。
&gt;&gt; We have something similar.
我们也有类似的计划。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So in the US if if you have a 401k
好的。在美国，如果你有401k
plan what you're going to find when you
计划，当你
open up your 401k plan is you have what
打开你的401k账户时，你会发现里面有
are called targetdated mutual funds.
所谓的目标日期共同基金。
This is a onestop mutual fund solution
这是一种一站式共同基金解决方案，可以满足
to your investing all the way until you
你从投资到
retire and it will be divided among
退休的所有需求。它会在
stocks and bonds and it will be what's
股票和债券之间进行分配，并且会随着
called rebalanced automatically as you
你
get closer to retirement. So, it'll go
临近退休而自动进行再平衡。所以，在
from being more stocks when you're
你年轻的时候，股票配置会比较多，
young, less stocks as you get older.
随着你年纪渐长，股票配置会逐渐减少。
There are trillions of dollars now in
现在，
these target date mutual funds. When I
这些目标日期共同基金的规模已经达到数万亿美元。
wrote the automatic miller 20 years ago,
20年前，我写了《自动磨坊主》这本书，当时它才刚刚
was just getting started. This automatic
起步。这种自动
solution to investing has changed the
投资方案改变了
game of investing for millions of
数百万美国人的投资方式
Americans. That's why there's 24 million
。这就是为什么
millionaires and that's why there's now
现在有2400万百万富翁，也是为什么
$45 trillion in retirement accounts.
退休账户总额高达45万亿美元。
&gt;&gt; We have a brain budget. The way to think
我们每个人的大脑都有“预算”。你可以这样理解：
about it is we have a limited amount of
我们
energy that we can spend every single
每天能消耗的能量是有限的
day. I'm saying find ways to simplify
。我的意思是，要找到简化
your life. And one way I've conserved my
生活的方法。我节省“预算”的方法之一
body budget is via our sponsor Factor
就是通过我们的赞助商Factor，
who are a meal delivery service. They
他们是一家送餐服务公司。他们
are especially great because they make
特别棒，因为他们提供
fresh meals and they cater to so many
新鲜的餐食，而且能满足各种
different diets. High protein, keto,
不同的饮食需求。高蛋白、生酮、
vegan, vegetarian, low carb,
纯素、素食、低碳水、
gluten-free, paleo diets, you name it.
无麸质、原始人饮食等等，应有尽有。
Every meal is designed by a dietitian,
每份餐食都由营养师设计，
made by chefs, and delivered right to
由厨师烹制，并直接送到
me. fresh and never frozen. So, if
我手中。新鲜，绝不冷冻。所以，如果
you're ready to streamline your food
你准备好简化你的
intake, visit factormeals.com/diary50
饮食，请访问factormeals.com/diary50
off and use my code diary50 off to get
，使用我的优惠码diary50，即可享受
50% off your first Factor box plus free
首个Factor餐盒5折优惠，外加免费赠品。
breakfast for 1 year. And this offer is
一年免费早餐。此优惠仅限使用
code and qualifying autoreview
优惠码并购买符合条件的自动审核
subscription purchase.
订阅的新客户。
Over the years, people have reached out
多年来，不断有人联系
asking me for mentorship. But the
我寻求指导。但
challenge I've always faced is that my
我面临的挑战是，我的
calendar doesn't permit me to help every
日程安排不允许我帮助每
single person that reaches out. So when
一位联系我的人。所以，当
I know I can't personally help, I try to
我知道自己无法亲自提供帮助时，我会尽力
push people towards tools that I think
推荐一些我认为
can. And that's why I wanted to tell you
可以提供帮助的工具。因此，我想向大家介绍
a little bit about a resource that I
一个我
think will be great for those of you who
认为对
are founders of small and medium-sized
中小企业创始人非常有益的资源
businesses. It's a content series that
。这是
our longtime show sponsor Vodafone has
我们长期赞助商沃达丰
created. It's called Vodafone
制作的系列内容，名为“Vodafone
Business.connected.
Business.connected”。
You'll find it on YouTube. This series
您可以在YouTube上找到它。该系列内容
delivers the knowledge that founders
旨在帮助创始人掌握
today need to grow their company in the
在数字时代发展公司所需的知识
digital age. There you'll learn about
。您将学习到
personal branding, cyber security,
个人品牌打造、网络安全、
scaling e-commerce companies, and
电子商务公司规模化等知识，并
through conversations with many founders
通过与
who I've invested in and work closely
我投资和密切合作的众多创始人的对话，让原本
with, the opaque picture of building a
模糊不清的
business will become clear. Some of
商业模式变得清晰明了。其中一些
those founders I've invested in in the
创始人…… 参与该
series include Cristiana Brenton from
系列投资的包括来自
Flight Story, Marissa Poster from
Flight Story 的 Cristiana Brenton、来自
Perfect Ted, Leo Harrison from Chapter
Perfect Ted 的 Marissa Poster、来自 Chapter 2 的 Leo Harrison
2, and Georgia Gibson, who I've
，以及我
partnered with to build Steven.com. And
合作创建 Steven.com 的 Georgia Gibson。
these are just a few of the great names
这只是众多优秀参与者中的一小部分
involved. Search Vodafone
。搜索 Vodafone
business.connected to learn more.
business.connected 了解更多信息。
The other book that you wrote which sold
你写的另一本书也卖得
incredibly incredibly well is this book
非常好，是
about smart couples finish rich. That's
关于聪明的夫妻如何致富的。
the title. Smart couples finish rich.
书名就是《聪明的夫妻如何致富：
Nine steps to creating a rich future for
为
you and your partner.
你和你的伴侣创造富裕未来的九个步骤》。这本书
&gt;&gt; As it relates to how rich or wealthy you
探讨了你最终的财富状况
become, the person you choose and the
、你选择的伴侣以及
way that you configure that
你们如何构建这段
relationship. How consequential is that?
关系。这有多重要？
&gt;&gt; It's everything
它真的至关重要
&gt;&gt; really.
。
&gt;&gt; It can be everything. Why?
它可以影响一切。为什么？
&gt;&gt; You're married. I'm married.
你结婚了。我也结婚了。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; So, why can it be everything?
那么，为什么它会影响一切呢？
&gt;&gt; Because here's what here's what happens
因为
in the real world, Stephen.
在现实世界中，Stephen，
&gt;&gt; Often we marry our financial opposite.
我们常常会和经济状况截然相反的人结婚。我以前经常给
lot of seminars for couples and I'd say
夫妻们做讲座，我常开玩笑说，
there's two types of people that are
人分两种类型。
born in the world. One person comes out
在这个世界上，有些人天生就喜欢
literally with a calculator and they're
用计算器，他们热爱
born to track where all the money goes
理财，
and they love to budget and they're
热衷于预算，
super excited about investing. That's
对投资也充满热情。这是其中一种
one kind of person. The other kind of
人。另一种
person loves to shop, loves to spend
人则热爱购物，喜欢
money. Almost inevitably those two
花钱。几乎可以肯定的是，这两种
people hook up. Now, sometimes two
人会走到一起。然而，有时两个
people who like to spend money marry.
爱花钱的人会结婚。
That's a disaster because they end up
这往往是一场灾难，因为他们最终会
broke. So now, what do you do about the
破产。那么，对于那些在理财观念上截然相反的伴侣，我们该怎么办呢
opposites?
？
That's what led to smart couples finish.
这就是“精明伴侣”这个概念的由来。
Because
因为
if you are married to your financial
如果你和你的理财观念截然
opposite, you will fight about money all
相反的人结婚，你们会一直为钱争吵
the time. And fights about money are
。而为钱争吵正是
what lead to divorce. They're the number
导致离婚的罪魁祸首。它是
one cause of divorce. The real key and
离婚的首要原因。真正的关键，也是
what I've been teaching now for over two
我
decades is the way you get couples on
二十多年来一直在教授的，是让伴侣在
the same page when it comes to money is
金钱问题上达成共识的方法，那就是从
you start with your values. So you look
你们的价值观入手。所以，你们要思考
together as a couple.
作为伴侣，你们真正最看重的是什么。
You put the money aside for a second.
暂时把金钱放在一边，仔细
You go through your values. What's most
审视你们的价值观。什么
important to you. What do you really
对你们来说最重要？你们真正
care about? You talk about your values.
关心的是什么？ 你们会谈谈自己的价值观，
And then you build a financial plan
然后围绕这些对你来说真正重要的东西制定财务计划
you.
。
&gt;&gt; You say that there's six worst money
你说夫妻最常犯的六个理财
mistakes that couples make. And the
错误，
first of those is not deciding who is
第一个就是没有明确分工。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
没错。很多时候，
So often in a relationship, one person
一段关系中，只有一方负责
pays the bills.
支付账单。
Okay,
那么，
who's managing the money? Now, I used to
谁来管理财务呢？我以前常
say in every household there should be
说，每个家庭至少应该有
at least one person that's paying the
一个人负责支付
bills and if the other person is
账单，如果另一个人
in charge of investments, that you still
负责管理财务，比如投资，你们也应该
get together and go through it. As I've
一起商量。随着
gotten older, I've really realized how
年龄的增长，我越来越意识到
important this is because I go back to
这一点的重要性，因为我发现
the fact that the average age is 59.
平均
Average age of widowhood is 59. I'm 59
丧偶年龄是59岁。我
now. I've had three best friends already
现在也59岁了。我已经失去了三个最好的朋友
pass away, all men, and they passed away
，他们都是男性，而且都不到
before they were 57. So, all these
57岁就去世了。所以，
statistics that I talk about, I'm seeing
我提到的这些统计数据，我亲眼目睹了
them come true. And I will tell
它们的发生。我
especially to the women, hear me loud,
尤其要对女性朋友们说，请你们听清楚，
hear me on this loud and clear, but this
请你们听清楚。 但这
is important for the men, too.
对男士来说也很重要。
hear. The question you have to ask
你需要问
yourself
自己的问题
is if your partner died today,
是，如果你的伴侣今天去世了，
what would you need to know about the
你需要了解哪些
finances?
财务信息？
And the answer is everything. Now, what
答案是：一切。
does that mean? Everything. That means
这是什么意思？一切。这意味着
you would need to know where is the
你需要知道
money.
钱都花在哪里。
Does he have money in an old 401k plan?
他是否在以前的401k计划里有钱？
Does he have money in IRA account? Does
他是否在个人退休账户（IRA）里有钱？他是否在银行账户里有钱？这些
accounts? Where's the will? You know,
账户的密码在哪里？遗嘱在哪里？你知道吗，
today don't have a will. You have to
今天在座的十个人里有六个没有遗嘱。无论年龄多大，你都必须立遗嘱。
&gt;&gt; At any age. If you, especially if you're
任何年龄。如果你，尤其是
in a relationship, you have to have a
有伴侣，你必须立
will. If you have kids, you have to have
遗嘱。如果你有孩子，你也必须立
a will. Is there life insurance? You
遗嘱。他有购买人寿保险吗？你
know, so many people today who have
知道吗，现在很多有
children don't have life insurance and
孩子的人都没有购买人寿保险，也
they don't have assets. You should at
没有资产。你至少应该
least get a million to$2 million term
购买一份保额在100万到200万美元之间的定期
policy. Super inexpensive. Protect your
寿险。非常便宜。保护你的
family. You have to run the drill,
家人。你必须认真对待这件事。
right? Like we got on a plane, we flew
对吧？就像我们
here today. The first thing they do on a
今天坐飞机来这里一样。飞机
plane before you take off is they talk
起飞前，第一件事就是讲解
emergency purposes. The mask's going to
紧急情况下的应对措施。比如，氧气面罩要
come down. You're going to put it on
摘下来，你要戴上
your face. Okay. You get on a cruise
。好。你坐上游轮，
boat. The first thing they do is talk
第一件事也是讲解
cruise boat's got a problem. You're
游轮出问题时的应对措施。你
going to go get in these emergency
要去登上
boats. You need to run the fire drill
救生艇。你还得
for your family on finances. I [snorts]
为家人进行财务方面的应急演练。我（哼）
almost died like it's now been four
差点就死了，那已经是四
years ago. I uh my wife found me face
年前的事了。我妻子发现我脸朝
down, passed out. I was brought to the
下昏迷不醒。我被送到
hospital in Florence. Um I was in a coma
佛罗伦萨的医院。我昏迷了
for four days. I was in the hospital for
四天，在医院住了
17. I had menitis. When I came out of
17天。我得了脑膜炎。醒来的时候，就像
just like a movie, I'm laying down. I
电影里演的那样，我躺在
mean, I'm laying down in the hospital.
医院里。
Doctor's looking over me. Doctor says,
医生正在检查我。医生问：
"Do you know what your name is?" I said,
“你知道你叫什么名字吗？”我说，
"It's David." He said, "Very good." He
“我是大卫。”他说，“很好。”他
goes, "Your last name is?" I said, "It's
又问，“你姓什么？”我说，“我姓
Boach." He says, "Do you know where you
博阿奇。”他说，“你知道你在哪里吗
are?" I go, "Yeah, I'm in Milan. I just
？”我说，“知道，我在米兰。” 我刚
had an ankle surgery." Because I had had
做了脚踝手术。”因为我
an ankle surgery two weeks prior, two
两周前，也就是再前两周，刚做过脚踝手术
two weeks before that. And he says, "No,
。然后他说：“不，
no, you're you're in Santa Maria Nolla.
不，你在圣玛丽亚诺拉。”
You're in the ICU. Uh we're treating you
你在重症监护室。 呃，我们现在正在给你治疗
right now for menitis, but now that
脑膜炎，但既然
you've opened up your eyes, you're going
你已经睁开眼睛了，
to be you're going to be okay. You're
你会没事的。 你
safe now." And then they brought my wife
现在安全了。”然后他们把我妻子带了
in. They said, "Do you know what her
进来。他们问：“你知道她叫什么
name is?" I and I made a joke. I said,
名字吗？”我开了个玩笑。我说：
"It's Rebecca." She was like, "Who?" I
“她叫丽贝卡。”她问：“谁？”我
go, "Honey, I can still be a smartass in
说：“亲爱的，即使在医院里我也可以耍嘴皮子
the hospital. It's Alatia." And she
。”  “是阿拉蒂亚。”她
starts screaming and yelling and she's
开始尖叫，大喊：
like, "Oh my god, oh my god, he's okay."
“我的天哪，我的天哪，他没事。”
But Stephen, the truth was I wasn't okay
但斯蒂芬，说实话，我当时并不好，
because when you get men and judges, you
因为男人和法官在一起，
get brain swelling. So I couldn't
脑子就会肿胀。所以我
remember things. I couldn't remember my
记不住事情。我记不起
passwords to the to the bank account. I
银行账户的密码。我甚至
didn't know the passwords to my phone
不知道手机密码了
number anymore, to my phone.
。
One of the things I did when I came out
我出院后做的一件事
of the hospital, because I always manage
，因为我一直负责
the money, is I said to my wife, "We're
理财，就是跟妻子说：“我们要
going to hire a financial advisor
请个财务顾问，
and you have to be involved in what's
你也必须参与
going on." We actually had yesterday our
进来。”我们昨天正好做了
annual account review. Because I tell
年度账户审查。因为我总是告诉
couples, you got to have an annual
夫妻，你们必须每年
account review either together and if
一起做一次账户审查，或者
you have a financial adviser at a
至少和你们的财务顾问一起做（如果你们有
minimum with your financial adviser. And
财务顾问的话）。
I didn't want to cancel the appointment
我不想取消预约，
because I was, even though you guys
因为，即使你们
invited me to come here, I'm like, I'm
邀请我来这里，我也想，我得去
keeping the appointment. We'll fly here
。我们
to flute this morning. And so again,
今天早上要飞过来吹长笛。所以 再说一遍，我
having worked at, you know, Morgan
在摩根
Stanley for nine years and been a
士丹利工作了九年，做过
financial adviser, I've seen too many
财务顾问，我见过太多
couples not do this,
夫妻没做到这一点，
including sadly Stephen, my dad just
包括我父亲斯蒂芬，很遗憾，我父亲
recently passed away. And my dad was in
最近去世了。我父亲一辈子都在做理财，
life. So he managed the money and my mom
所以他负责管理钱，而我母亲
was not involved. And when my dad passed
却不参与。父亲去世后
away, we had to just like my book, step
，我们不得不像我书里写的那样，接手
in and help my mom with everything. Now,
所有的事情来帮助我母亲。现在
she's lucky. She's got two kids in the
她很幸运，她的两个孩子也从事这个
business, but she didn't. My mom was
行业，但她自己却没有。我母亲就是
just a ripe waiting example of somebody
一个很
who could be taken advantage of. So, the
容易被人利用的例子。所以，
time to learn about money is before
学习理财的最佳时机是在
there's a problem. If you took smart
问题出现之前。如果你读过《精明
couples finish honestly Stephen that you
夫妻》（Smart Couples）这本书，斯蒂芬，你会发现它就像一份
it's it's designed to be a a roadmap for
路线图，是为
two people together where you can sit
两个人共同设计的，你们可以
down and go through this book chapter by
坐下来，一章一
chapter together starting with just
章地一起阅读。首先是
organizing your financial information
整理你们的财务信息，
putting everything into file folders
把所有东西都放进文件夹里，这可以
starts the conversation and then talking
开启对话，然后谈谈
about your values then talking about
你们的价值观，再谈谈你们的
your dreams then going into well what
梦想，最后谈谈
what do you want to share you know you
你们想分享什么。我知道你们
have a very comp I don't know all your
有很多共同点，我不知道全部。 你的
stuff, but I've followed you for years.
节目我虽然没怎么关注，但我关注你好几年了。
As I told you, I'm a fan of yours. I've
就像我之前跟你说过的，我是你的粉丝。
got your book. I've watched your
你的书我买了，你的
podcast. I've listened to you now for
播客我看了，你的节目我听了好
years. As your business is expanding,
几年了。随着你的事业发展，
your life is getting more complicated.
你的生活也变得越来越复杂。万一
God forbid something happens to you
你明天出了什么事呢？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. It'd be a [__] nightmare.
天哪，那简直就是一场噩梦。
&gt;&gt; And she's your fiance.
而且她是你的未婚妻。是
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
啊，
&gt;&gt; She wouldn't even know where to start.
她都不知道该怎么办。
&gt;&gt; And I don't know if she would know who
我也不知道她该找谁
to call.
帮忙。
So, it's a worthwhile conversation. like
所以，这确实值得好好聊聊。就像
I just had this guy in the show and I
我刚才节目里请了一个人，我觉得
don't know maybe maybe we really need to
我们或许真的应该让
like need to involve you a little bit.
你也参与进来。
&gt;&gt; I was just looking at some of the data
我刚才看了些数据，
ignorance according to a 2021 study by
根据富达投资2021年的一项研究，在收入认知方面，
Fidelity Investments nearly 40% of
近40%的
couples could not even identify how much
夫妻甚至不知道
their partner earned. It says in terms
对方的收入是多少。在
of financial infidelity, surveys from
财务不忠方面，
bank rate and creditcards.com
Bank Rate和Creditcards.com的调查也
consistently find that up to 40% of
一致发现，高达……  40%的
adults share that they have kept
成年人表示他们曾对伴侣隐瞒
financial secrets which is hiding cash,
财务秘密，例如藏匿现金、
hiding bank statements and hiding debts
银行账单和债务
partner. So that's almost half and you
。这几乎占到一半，正如你
pointed at this earlier on which is the
之前提到的，这就是所谓的“
CFO dynamic. In many households, one
首席财务官”模式。在很多家庭中，
spouse acts as the chief financial
夫妻一方扮演着首席财务官的角色
officer. And research indicates that
。研究表明，
roughly 50% of couples um have a
大约50%的夫妻一方并不
non-managing spouse who has little to no
负责财务管理，他们对
idea how much money the family have
家庭
total. They don't know where it is and
总资产知之甚少甚至一无所知。他们不知道钱在哪里，
they don't know the passwords.
也不知道密码。
&gt;&gt; It can sound scary. It can sound
这听起来可能很可怕，甚至令人
intimidating. And yet, I can tell you
望而生畏。然而，我可以告诉你，
every day, people who actually kind of
每天都有人真正
do this basic stuff that we've talked
做到我们刚才讨论的这些基本理财方法。
about, once you start to do it, you feel
一旦你开始这样做，你就会感觉好很多
a lot better. You feel better instantly.
。你会立刻感觉好很多。
You don't you don't have to go from
你不需要从
having no savings to having a million
一无所有到拥有百万
dollars to feel better. If you just
美元才能感觉好一些。如果你
start automatically saving some money,
开始自动存钱，
paying yourself first. The moment you
优先给自己支付，那么当你
make that decision, you'll feel better.
做出这个决定的那一刻，你就会感觉好很多。
subscription fees like you just looked
就像你刚才提到的，你可以取消一些订阅费用
at. The moment you do that, you'll feel
。 你这样做，你会感觉
better. It's literally like a financial
好些。这就像锻炼财务
muscle. You start to build this
肌肉一样。当你开始行动时，你就能锻炼出这种
financial muscle when you start to take
财务肌肉
action. It is action that changes your
。正是行动改变了你的
life. I always say I wrote all these
人生。我常说，我写了这么多
books. If a person buys a book, reads it
书。如果一个人买了一本书，读了之后却什么
and doesn't do anything, then I was a
也不做，那我只不过是一种
form of entertainment.
娱乐而已。
If you listen to a podcast on money and
如果你听了一个关于理财的播客，却
you don't do something, then we were
什么也不做，那我们同样也只是
again a form of entertainment.
一种娱乐而已。
My purpose for doing this podcast today,
我今天做这个播客的目的，也是
why I got on a plane and flew out here
我为什么立刻飞到这里和
immediately to do this with you was I
你们一起做这个播客的原因，就是我
want to try to change somebody's life
想尝试改变某人的生活
today. I've always taken the approach of
。我一直以来都秉持着这样的理念：
like I want to change a person's life
我想一次改变一个人的生活
one person at a time. And sometimes the
。有时候
things I share are hard to hear, but I
我分享的内容可能很难接受，但我
also know they wake people up. You had
知道它们能唤醒人们。你
this great great quote in this book. I
在这本书里有一句很棒的话。
was showing this today to my son.
今天我把它拿给我儿子看。
I'm holding, for those of you who can't
我手里拿着——可能有些人
see me, I'm holding Steven's book, A
看不到我——我手里拿着的是史蒂文的书，《
Diary of the CEO, which has also sold
CEO日记》，这本书也卖出了
millions of copies. And this is your
数百万册。 你
quote on page 233. I wonder if you
在第233页引用的那句话。我很好奇你是否还
remember your quotes because sometimes
记得自己说过的话，因为有时候
you forget them, right?
你会忘记，对吧？
If you want long-term success in
如果你想在
business, relationships, and life, you
事业、人际关系和生活中取得长期的成功，就
have to get better at accepting
必须
uncomfortable truths as fast as
尽快学会接受那些令人不舒服的真相
possible.
。
When you refuse to accept an
当你拒绝接受这些令人不舒服的
uncomfortable truth, you are choosing to
真相时，你就是在选择
accept an uncomfortable future.
接受一个令人不舒服的未来。
The one thing that wasn't in this quote
这句话里唯一没有提到的就是
was money.
金钱。
And everything we're talking about is
而我们一直在讨论的，
I'm like, you're gonna work 90,000 hours
我的意思是，你一生要工作9万个小时
over your lifetime. If you don't pay
。如果你不先给
yourself first and you have nothing to
自己发工资，最终一无所获
show for it, the uncomfortable truth is
，那么残酷的真相就是
you will be broke. We haven't talked
你会破产。我们还没有谈到
about um global issues and government
全球问题、政府
issues and debt.
问题和债务。
Why do you have to take care of yourself
为什么你
financially right now more than ever
现在比以往任何时候都更需要照顾好自己的财务状况
before?
？
Because the future is about to radically
因为未来即将发生翻天覆地的
change. And I will talk out of both
变化。我接下来要自相矛盾地说两件事
sides of my mouth for a second. Number
。首先
one, I believe the next 10 years, hands
，我相信未来十年绝对是
to build wealth in our lifetime. AI is
我们一生中积累财富的最佳时机。人工智能
create going to create so much wealth
将会创造前所未有的巨额财富。
Like when you look at the returns in the
就像你看看
stock market from last year, they're a
去年股市的回报，那都是
result of AI. What's happening is AI is
人工智能带来的结果。人工智能正在
making companies more profitable and
让公司比以往任何时候都更盈利、
more productive than they've ever been.
更高效。但
The downside is people are losing their
缺点是，人们正在
jobs, right? You've had people on the
失业，对吧？
show including Tony Robbins talking
节目中，包括托尼·罗宾斯在内的许多人都谈到了
about this and there are going to be a
这一点，而且
lot more of those job losses. So some
失业人数还会继续增加。所以有些
people are going to get much wealthier
人会变得更加富有，
and then a whole lot of other people are
而另一些人则会
going to have a challenge. But there's
面临挑战。但
another problem that we we're not
我们还没有
talking enough about and that is the
充分讨论另一个问题，那就是
safety nets of governments.
政府的社会保障体系。
in the US, Social Security,
美国设立的这些社会保障体系，比如社会保障、
Medicare, Medicaid,
医疗保险、医疗补助、
unemployment, you can go to through
失业救济金等等，在
every single country.
每个国家都存在。
All of these things are called
所有这些都被称为
entitlement programs, which is a fancy
福利项目，
word for saying the government made a
说白了就是政府
promise to you.
对你做出了承诺。
And a whole lot of people are dependent
很多人都依赖
on that promise and there's not enough
于这些承诺，但
money to pay for those promises. So like
资金却不足以兑现这些承诺。就拿
in the US, you take social security. The
美国的社会保障来说，
average social security check right now
目前平均的社会保障金
is $1,900.
是……  1900美元。这笔
Not a lot of money, but about 60 million
钱不算多，但大约有6000万
Americans
美国人
depend on that amount of money.
依靠这笔钱生活。
In the US, Social Security, this is
在美国，社会保障体系——这是
government data, not me. you can do all
政府数据，不是我说的。你可以
this stuff online.
在网上查到所有这些信息。
The government is telling us that in
政府告诉我们，到
2033, that's around the corner, the
2033年（很快就到了），
Social Security is going to be
社会保障资金将
underfunded and they're going to have to
不足，他们不得不
cut the benefits. Now, what they're
削减福利。他们
talking about is cutting the benefits by
说的是削减
20%. You have a lot of Americans that
20%的福利。这对很多美国人来说将
that's going to be a real problem for
是一个真正的问题，
every country's got this issue because
每个国家都面临着这个问题，因为
people are living longer. Governments
人们的寿命越来越长。各国政府的
have more debt than they've ever had. I
债务也比以往任何时候都多。我要
am here to tell you,
告诉你们，虽然
it's a cliche term, but no one's coming
这是句老生常谈，但没有人会来
to save you. It's you're gonna have to
拯救你们。你们必须
save yourself and you're gonna have to
自救，必须比以往任何时候都
more seriously now than ever before. And
更加重视自己的财务状况。
if you do, you will be in great shape.
如果你们这样做，你们的财务状况就会很好。
If you don't, you will be dependent on a
如果你们不这样做，你们将依赖于一个
system that is buckling.
摇摇欲坠的体系。
One of the things in your I think it's
你们需要做的其中一件事是…… 我认为
couples get wrong is waiting too long to
夫妻常犯的六大错误之一就是拖延
pay off the mortgage. What do you mean
还清房贷。你这话是什么意思
by that? I actually had a friend contact
？我有个朋友联系
me um and asked this. They said,
我问过这个问题。他说：
"Stephen, I've got some cash that that's
“斯蒂芬，我收到了一笔钱
been given to me." I think through an
。” 我想应该是
inheritance. Should I pay off my
继承来的。我应该用来还清
mortgage or should I go invest in the
房贷，还是应该投资
stock market in the S&amp;P 500 or something
标普500指数之类的股票
else?
？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是啊。
&gt;&gt; And I didn't know what to say because
我不知道该怎么回答，因为
I'm not a financial adviser.
我不是理财顾问。
&gt;&gt; So, if you called me up and you said,
所以，如果你打电话问我：
"David, what what should I do?" I'd go,
“大卫，我该怎么办？”我会说：
"Stephen, what's the rate on your
“斯蒂芬，你的房贷利率是多少
mortgage?" Then you'd say, "Well, David,
？”然后你会说：“大卫，
I got a mortgage 5 years ago and it's 2
我五年前办的房贷，利率是
and a half%." And I'd say, "Okay, well
2.5%。”我会说：“好的，
that's a really low rate, Stephen. You
斯蒂芬，这利率真的很低。” 你
know what? You can put the money in a
知道吗？ 你现在就可以把这笔钱存入
money market account right now and make
货币市场账户，赚取
more than that. So maybe you don't need
更多收益。 所以，也许你不需要
to rush to pay it off as fast as
急着尽快还清贷款
possible." But if you've got a mortgage
。但如果你的房贷利率是
at six or seven or eight%, it's a
6%、7%甚至8%，那就
no-brainer. The biggest thing I can tell
显而易见了。关于提前还清房贷，我能告诉你的最重要一点
early is actually really simple. Here's
其实很简单。
ways to do it. If you make one extra
方法如下：如果你
payment a year on a mortgage, you'll
每年多还一次房贷，那么即使是30年的房贷，你也能提前
it off, depends on the rate, five, six,
5、6、
seven years sooner.
7年还清，具体时间取决于利率。
So, you can go online, you can run a
你可以上网，用
calculator. Today, you don't even need
计算器算一下。现在，你甚至不需要
calculator. You just run the question.
计算器。你只需要输入
You put in your mortgage. You tell
你的房贷信息。告诉
Gemini, here's the size of my mortgage.
Gemini，这是我的房贷金额，
Here's my mortgage payment. If I make an
这是我的每月还款额。如果我
extra payment a year, how many how many
每年多还一次，
years faster will I pay it off? And how
我能提前多少年还清？
much will I save? And you'll see the
我能省多少钱？然后你就能看到
number. When people see the number in
结果。当人们看到这些
black and white, they go, "I've got to
白纸黑字的数字时，他们会想：“我必须
do that." Now, here's the key. Make that
这么做。”关键就在这里：把这笔还款设置成
payment automatic.
自动转账。
The easiest way you make your payment
最简单的方法是…… 让你的还款
automatic is either make one extra
自动进行，要么是
payment at the end of the year or take
在年底额外支付一次，要么是将
your mortgage payment and increase it by
你的房贷月供增加
10%. So, if your mortgage payment is
10%。例如，如果你的房贷月供是
$1,000, make an $1,100 a month mortgage
1000美元，那就每月支付1100美元，
payment and tell the bank you want to
并告诉银行你想把
add that to the principal. When people
这笔钱加到本金里。
do that, they need to make sure though
不过，这样做的人需要确保
that money is actually paying down the
这笔钱确实用于偿还
principal. And another way to do that is
本金。另一种方法是
a bi-weekly mortgage payment plan where
双周还款计划，也就是
you take your mortgage, you split in
将你的房贷分
half, you pay half every two weeks.
成两半，每两周支付一半。
That'll also pay your mortgage off
这样也能提前还清房贷
early.
。
&gt;&gt; Prenuptual agreements. I'm engaged.
婚前协议。我订婚了。
&gt;&gt; Yep.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Should I be getting a prenup?
我应该签婚前协议吗？
&gt;&gt; So, I would tell anyone who's getting
我会告诉所有即将
married,
结婚的人：
number one, if your incomes are not the
第一，如果你们的收入
same, you should get a prenup. Number
不同，就应该签婚前协议。
two, if you both have good incomes, you
第二，如果你们双方收入都不错，就
should get a prenup. Number three, if
应该签婚前协议。第三，如果
you're in your 30s, you should get a
你已经30多岁了，就应该签
prenup. You would never go into a
婚前协议。你不会在
business without a contract.
没有合同的情况下开展业务。
Marriage is the ultimate contract. It
婚姻就是最终的合同。 就是这样
just is. Now, is it romantic to do a
。那么，签
prenuptual agreement? No. [snorts]
婚前协议浪漫吗？不浪漫。[嗤之以鼻]
typically not like the doing a prenup?
通常情况下，恋爱关系中的一方会不喜欢签婚前协议吗？
Yes. I know a lot of women today who
是的。我知道现在很多女性
want prenups and the husbands don't want
想要签婚前协议，但她们的丈夫却不同意
them. It's whoever's making the money.
。这完全取决于谁挣钱。
But I will say this about prenups. You
但我必须说，关于婚前协议，你
need a lawyer. She needs a lawyer. You
需要律师。她也需要律师。你
cannot go and do a prenup right before
不能在结婚前才去签婚前协议
you get married. When people do that,
。如果这样做，
those prenups get thrown out the window
这些协议就会被作废，
because they will claim and say and have
因为他们会声称，并
an argument for, I was under
辩称，我在
agreement before the wedding. And those
结婚前签署这份协议时受到了极大的不正当影响。
agreements get thrown out even if
即使协议中有
there's disclaimer language. And both of
免责声明，这些协议也会被作废。
you need attorneys.
你们双方都需要律师。
And prenuptual agreements can often be
而且，婚前协议往往
like a negotiation. And you can learn a
就像一场谈判。你会从中了解到
lot about your partner that it's not
很多关于你伴侣的事情，而这些事情并不
always pretty. I'm not saying you, but
总是那么美好。我不是说你，但当
that's not always pretty when you do a
你签
prenuptual agreement. And once the
婚前协议时，你会了解到很多关于你伴侣的事情，而这些事情并不总是那么美好。一旦……
prenuptual agreement is done, if it's a
婚前协议签好了，如果是一份
reasonable prenuptual agreement, it goes
合理的婚前协议，就会
in a file. It doesn't get looked at
存档。之后就不会再被翻看
again. And it won't matter unless the
。除非
day comes that you need to pull it out.
有一天你需要用到它，否则它不会有任何作用。
And that's for a firsttime marriage.
这指的是初婚。
Okay, you're a second time marriage or a
好吧，如果你是二婚或
third time marriage and you've got kids
三婚，有孩子、有
and custody issues and and and support
监护权问题，还要赡养
for your first wife. You definitely need
前妻，那你肯定需要
a prenup.
一份婚前协议。
&gt;&gt; What is the most important thing we
我们应该谈但没谈的最重要的事情是什么
talk about?
？
&gt;&gt; Stephen, we've talked a lot about money
斯蒂芬，我们今天谈了很多关于钱的事
today, but money is just a tool. So,
，但钱只是一种工具。所以，
what we actually haven't got to talk a
我们真正没怎么谈的
lot about is using money just to free
是如何利用金钱让
yourself to live your best life. And you
自己过上最好的生活。你
don't have to have money to live your
不需要拥有很多钱也能过上
best life. Again, money is just a tool.
最好的生活。再说一遍，钱只是一种工具。
So, what's most important in life? I'm
那么，生活中最重要的是什么？我会
going to say things that people know.
说一些大家都知道的事情。
Health. You I started following you
健康。我关注你是
because of all the shows you did on
因为你做的所有关于
health.
健康的节目。
Love.
爱。
People hold on to love way too much.
人们对爱的执着太深了。
Gratitude.
感恩。
Being consistently grateful for the life
始终对
you have. Friendship.
你所拥有的生活心怀感激。友谊。
loving your friends fully
全心全意地爱你的朋友，
and the la last thing is fun. You know,
最后一点是乐趣。你知道，
I think people go through life and at
我觉得人们在人生旅途中，总会在
some point they stop designing their
某个时刻停止规划自己的
life. My grandmother used to say, you
人生。我奶奶常说，你
got to dream it, design it, and do it.
要梦想它，规划它，然后去实现它。
And she's like, you're going to run out
她还说，你的
of time. So what I would say to anybody
时间会不够用。所以我想对所有人说的是，
is like this is you've got this one
你拥有这
beautiful moment in time where you're
美好的时光，你现在就在
here.
这里。
What do you want?
你想要什么？从
And start working on that today.
今天开始为之努力。
&gt;&gt; You listen to the episode with Tony
你听过托尼·罗宾斯的那期节目吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; You've referenced him several times in
你在这次谈话中多次提到他
this conversation. If someone were to
。如果有人
ask me who was the greatest mentor and
问我，
besides my grandmother and my father,
除了我的祖母和父亲之外，谁是我生命中最伟大的导师和影响最大的人，
it's Tony Robbins. So I went to Tony
那就是托尼·罗宾斯。我
Robbins seminars in the early 90s back
在90年代初参加过托尼·罗宾斯的研讨会，
in the day when he had an infomercial
那时候他还在电视购物节目里播放录音带
with audio cassettes.
。
And I went to a program that he taught
我还参加过他在夏威夷举办的一个项目
in Hawaii. He had this big hotel called
。他有一家叫亚洛亚的大酒店
the Yaloa. And he did it he did an
。他在那里举办了一个……
exercise. This is so I it's like I
练习。这感觉就像
remember like this yesterday. He said to
昨天发生的一样。他当时在
this the room we were in and there were
我们所在的房间里，大概有
I don't know a thousand of us in this
一千人吧
room. He said, "How many of you have a
。他说：“你们当中有多少人有一个
dream that you're not working on?" And
没有付诸行动的梦想？”
we all we all had dreams like and so he
我们每个人都有自己的梦想，于是他
got us into a peak state and he had us
让我们进入最佳状态，然后让我们开始为
work on our dreams. And then he asked
自己的梦想努力。接着他
the question, "How many of you think
又问：“你们当中有多少人认为
you're going to be alive in 10 years?"
自己还能活到十年后？”
Everyone's like, "Yeah, I'm going be
每个人都说：“是的，我还能活到
alive in 10 years." He's like, "Great.
十年后。”他说：“太好了。”
So I got a question for you.
我有个问题想问你。
Are you going to be alive in 10 years
10年后，你是否还能活着，并且为实现
having worked on your dream?
梦想而努力？
Hopefully gotten it right, done all the
希望你做对了，完成了
things I've taught you to do, you know,
我教你的所有事情，你知道，
modeled the masters, got yourself in
模仿大师们，让自己达到
peak state, learned the pattern
最佳状态，学会了
recognition.
模式识别。
Have you gotten 10 years older having
你是否在实现梦想的过程中，不知不觉地老了10岁，甚至
gone through your dreams and maybe got
可能梦想成真了
it? Or did you just get 10 years over 10
？ 还是说你只是白白老了十岁，
years older and you let your dream die?
然后就让你的梦想破灭了？
you let your dream die and the room he
你让你的梦想破灭了，他
just let that sit and then he had us go
让那个房间就那样静静地待着，然后他让我们
off in groups of 10 and share our
十个人一组，分享我们
individual dream. So we'd all written it
各自的梦想。 所以我们都把它写在了
down on paper. So I shared that my dream
纸上。 所以我分享了我的梦想，
and this young kid financial adviser I'm
我是一个年轻的财务顾问
a guy. I shared my dream was to write a
。 我曾分享过我的梦想，那就是写一本
book called Smart Women Finish Rich and
名为《聪明女人致富》的书，
teach a million women to be smart with
教导一百万女性如何聪明地
money so they could protect themselves,
理财，从而保护自己、
teach their kids, and help their family.
教育孩子、帮助家人。
My heart's pounding, Stephen. I'm
斯蒂芬，我的心跳得好快。 我要把
sharing this idea with 10 strangers. And
这个想法分享给10个陌生人。
then we go back into the room and he's
然后我们回到房间，他
like, "How'd that go? Are you guys all
问：“怎么样？你们都
ready?" Gets us back in a peak state. 10
准备好了吗？” 让我们重回巅峰状态。 十分
minutes later, a woman comes, taps me on
钟后，一个女人走过来，拍了拍我的
the shoulder, and she says, "I just
肩膀，说：“我刚
heard about your dream. My name's Vicki.
听说了你的梦想。我叫维姬，
I've worked on Tony's last two books. If
我参与了托尼最近两本书的制作。如果
you want to do your book, you're gonna
你想出书，你
need a book proposal. You've done books,
需要一份图书提案。你写过书，应该
you know this. She's like, I can help
知道这一点。” 她说：“我可以帮
you write a book proposal. I hired her.
你写一份图书提案。” 我雇了她，
I started working on that book proposal.
开始着手撰写那份提案。
Later, I would go after the same agent
后来，我联系了
that Tony has, Jan Miller. She'd become
托尼的经纪人简·米勒，她成了
my agent. He'd write a cover letter. I'd
我的经纪人。她帮我写了一封求职信。我
get a book deal, and I'd start working
拿到了出版合同，开始着手
to help millions of people. It started
帮助数百万人。这一切都始于
at a Tony Robbins seminar. And I go back
托尼·罗宾斯的一次研讨会。这要追溯到
to my grandmother, right? Dream it,
我的祖母，对吧？梦想它，
design it, and do it.
设计它，然后去做。
He gave me the life skills to do that.
他给了我实现梦想所需的生活技能。
And I will tell you something about Tony
我还要跟你说说托尼，
because you know, you see Tony on all
因为你知道，你在各种节目里都能看到托尼，
these shows and people go, "Is Tony the
人们会问：“托尼是
real deal?" I Stephen, if I if I was
真的吗？” 斯蒂芬，如果我和
with you and I send Tony a text and I
你在一起，我给托尼发了条短信，我
and Tony has a lot of friends like this,
和托尼有很多话要说。 像托尼这样的朋友，他总是能及时
Tony gets right back to me. Tonyy's the
回复我。托尼真是个
real deal. I just went to Germany and
好人。我刚去了趟德国，
took my older son Jack who's 22 to see
带我22岁的大儿子杰克去看
him do UPW in September could bring
他九月份的UPW活动，我当时都快
tears to my eyes because I wanted Jack
哭了，因为我想让杰克在
to have the experience without me there.
没有我陪伴的情况下也能体验这一切。
So he was, you know, bless Tony sitting
所以，你知道，托尼坐在
in the front row. I came in on day three
前排，真是太好了。我是在
when he was in the peak state and I came
他状态巅峰的第三天去的，
in and I watched him, you know, I was
我看着他，你知道，我当时和
basically his age and I thought, God,
他差不多大，我心想，天哪，
you don't, you know, I went in, I gave
你根本想象不到。我走过去，给了
him a hug and I'm like, you just don't
他一个拥抱，我说，你根本无法想象
even know. This is just this experience
。
that you're seeing, what you're learning
你今天所看到的，你所学到的
today, if you use this stuff, it will
，如果你能运用这些，它会
change your life.
改变你的人生。
That's the power of Tony. And people go,
这就是托尼的力量。人们会说
you know, whatever it is, your podcast,
，不管是什么，你的播客，
your events, Tony's events, my books,
你的活动，托尼的活动，我的书，
we're just catalysts.
我们都只是催化剂。
But God
但
God gave you a seed and a dream. And
上帝给了你一颗种子和一个梦想。
when we're the catalyst for like, look,
当我们成为催化剂，鼓励你
go do this. Listen to that voice.
去做这件事，听听他的话时，我们就能发挥更大的作用。 那个声音。
Whoever your God is, that soul that you
无论你信仰的神是谁，你内心深处那个声音，就是你对
hear yourself saying, I have a dream. If
自己说：“我有一个梦想。如果
I only had 10 years left to live, I
我只剩下十年的寿命，我
would really hate to die with that dream
真的不想带着这个梦想死去
inside me. That's the dream you go work
。” 那就是你要为之奋斗的梦想。
&gt;&gt; And since then, you've done exactly
从那时起，你就一直在
that. You've educated hundreds of
这样做。你
millions of people through your books,
通过书籍、
through podcast, seminars, newsletters,
播客、研讨会、简报
and thousands of media appearances on
以及数千次媒体露面，教育了数亿人
how to do exactly that. How to get
如何实现这个梦想。如何获得
financially free, pursue their dreams,
财务自由，追逐梦想，
get hold of their money so that they can
掌控自己的金钱，从而过上
live the life that is um destined for
命中注定的生活
them. And that is an incredible thing.
。这真是太了不起了。
And you've sold almost 10 million copies
你的书在全球的销量已经接近一千万册
of your books worldwide. I'm sure you're
。我相信你
soon. And uh I guess you'll never get to
很快就会达到这个数字。我想你永远也无法亲眼
see the impact that that's had on so
目睹你的书对这么
many people's lives and how you've
多人的生活产生了多么巨大的影响，以及你如何
therefore changed the trajectory of
改变了
their financial future and their kids
他们、他们的子孙后代的财务未来轨迹，就像
and their kids and their kids like your
你的
grandmother did for you and your family.
祖母改变了你和你的家人一样。
I'd highly recommend everybody go and
我强烈建议大家去
listen to that episode. I'm actually
听听你的书。 说到那一集，我其实会在
going to link it below. So if you
下面放链接。所以如果你
haven't listened to the episode with
还没听过
Tony Robbins, that's a great next thing
托尼·罗宾斯那一集，
to do if you're still listening now. But
如果你现在还在听，那接下来就去听听吧。
uh David, I wanted to thank thank you so
大卫，非常感谢你
much for coming and uh you present a
来做客，你对金钱这个话题提出了一个
really interesting different perspective
非常有趣且独特的视角，这
on the subject of money which is is hard
很难
to find. It's rare um but it's very very
得。这种视角很罕见，但它非常非常
very important and I'm hopefully it'll
重要，我希望它能
be consequential for many. We have a
对很多人产生影响。你知道，我们有个
closing tradition as you know um where
结束环节的传统，就是
we ask the next guest the question left
问下一位嘉宾上一位嘉宾留下的问题，
by the last and the question left for
而留给你的问题很
interesting. If you had all the money
有意思。如果你拥有足够的钱来
you needed to have to support yourself
养活自己
and your family, zero financial
和家人，没有任何经济上的
worries, what job profession would you
担忧，你
be doing? Or rather, what would you
会从事什么职业？或者更确切地说，你会把
spend your time on? [laughter]
时间花在什么事情上？[笑声]
you're giving me that that was asked
你问我的这个问题，竟然是
before I got here. Like that's that's a
我来之前有人问过的，这真是太不可思议了。这简直就是
God moment, too. Like that's meant to
天意，仿佛是命中注定。
be.
顺便说一句， 我可没
up.
瞎编。
cuz that's me. I have enough. I have all
因为这就是我。我拥有足够的财富。我有足够的
the money that I need. I have my health
钱。我现在身体健康
right now. I have my time. And this
。我有充足的时间。
year, what am I going to what what I
今年，我要做什么？我
want to go do my dream for the year? I
要实现我今年的梦想吗？我
want to have an endless ski season. So,
想要一个永无止境的滑雪季。所以，
at the end of the year, ask me, did I
到年底的时候，你们可以问我，我
ski somewhere every month this year? I
今年每个月都去滑雪了吗？
leave you today. I go back to Florence
今天就到此为止。我会回佛罗伦萨
for 24 hours and I turn around, go to
待24小时，然后
Verbier, Switzerland with friends. I'm
和朋友们一起去瑞士的韦尔比耶。
every month this year with friends and
今年，我要和朋友、
with family all around the world for
家人一起，在世界各地，每天、每个月都去滑雪，享受滑雪的
fun. I did this as my last dream to help
乐趣。我把这当作我的最后一个梦想，希望能帮助新一代
one more generation be smart with their
人更好地
money. This is my final book. This may
理财。这是我的最后一本书。这或许也是
be my final podcast. And what you've
我的最后一个播客。你
done is you've updated your smash hit
所做的，是更新了
copies that you wrote 20 years ago to
你20年前写的那本销量数百万册的畅销书，
make it relevant to the current
让它与
financial situation and world that we
我们所处的当今经济形势和世界息息相关
live in.
。
&gt;&gt; And my goal with this was a lot of my
我的目标是…… 我的很多
readers now in their 50s and their 60s,
读者现在都五六十岁了，
but they've got young kids like I do and
但他们和我一样，都有年幼的孩子，所以
I wanted this to be a book they can put
我希望这本书能让他们也能
in their hands.
读到。
&gt;&gt; I'm going to link the book below.
我会在下面附上书的链接。这本书
Fantastic read. You've written several
太棒了！您写过好几本
incredible books. So, it's I'm going to
非常精彩的书。所以，我会在
link all of them below in the
下面的
[clears throat] description for anyone
[清嗓子]简介里把所有书的链接都放上来，方便大家
that wants to grab a copy of them. The
购买。 《
Automatic Millionaire, a powerful
自动百万富翁》，一个强有力的
one-step plan to live and finish Rich.
一步计划，教你如何生活并最终致富。
David, thank you.
大卫，谢谢你。
&gt;&gt; Stephen, thank you. It's been great.
斯蒂芬，谢谢你。这段经历很棒。
&gt;&gt; I'm going to show you how to get clear
我会教你如何明确
on what you really want, figure out
自己真正想要的是什么，找出阻碍
what's been stopping you, put the plan
你前进的因素，制定计划
in place, and teach you the most
，并教你
important thing that's made me
让我成功的最重要的一点
successful.
。
&gt;&gt; And I don't think people fully realize
而且，我认为人们并没有充分意识到
influential people on planet Earth you
你曾与地球上许多最具影响力的人物
have worked with and continue to work
合作过，并且现在仍在与他们合作
with. What is the pattern that you
。你
noticed in those people?
在这些人身上发现了什么共同点？